( 懸賞  不論死活 ) 這個人價值五百美元
This man is worth $500,
而此人要去拿賞金
and this man's going to collect.
他叫傑克·卡希爾  他只遵守...
He's Jake Cahill, and he lives by...
"賞金律法"
Bounty Law.
你都不留活口的吧  傑克
You don't ever bring them in alive, do you, Jake?
我可是一個打三個
Not when there's three of them and one of me.
看什麼看  賞金殺手?
What are you looking at, bounty killer?
我在看一個下巴將被打爆的醜老賊
I'm looking at an ugly owl-hoot about to get his jaw busted.
業餘的會想留活口
Amateurs try and take men in alive.
業餘的通常都活不下來
Amateurs usually don't make it.
在《賞金律法》裡  對傑克·卡希爾來說
Whether you're dead or alive,
不管你是死是活  你只是個金錢符號
you're just a dollar sign to Jake Cahill on Bounty Law.
週四晚間8點30分  於國家廣播公司獨家播映
Thursdays at 8:30, only on NBC.
大家好  我是艾倫·金凱德
Hello, everybody. This is Allen Kincade
我們在國家廣播公司與幕寶電視公司的精彩大戲《賞金律法》拍攝現場
on the set of the exciting hit NBC and Screen Gems television series Bounty Law.
如果你以為你眼花
Now, if you think you're seeing double,
不用調整電視機  因為你是真的看見重影了
don't adjust your television sets because, well, in a way, you are.
我的右邊是主角傑克·卡希爾本人  瑞克·達爾頓
To my right is Bounty Law series lead and Jake Cahill himself, Rick Dalton.
我的左邊是瑞克的特技替身  克裡夫·布茲
And to my left is Rick's stunt double, Cliff Booth.
歡迎兩位  謝謝你們抽空與我們見面
Welcome and thanks for taking the time to visit with us.
這是我們的榮幸  艾倫
It's our pleasure, Allen.
瑞克  向觀眾解釋一下  特技替身的工作究竟是什麼
So, Rick, explain to the audience exactly what it is a stunt double does.
嗯...
Well...
演員通常需要做很多危險的事
actors are required to do a lot of dangerous stuff.
例如傑克·卡希爾從馬上被射下來
Say Jake Cahill gets shot off his horse.
那麼  我即將從馬上跌下來嗎?
Now, can I fall off a horse?
有可能  我跌下來過
Yes, I can, and, yes, I have.
但要是我出了差錯  扭傷手腕
But say I fall off wrong and I sprain my wrist
或扭傷腳踝
or I... or I twist my ankle.
這樣會造成拍片時不必要的負擔
( 劇組因此停工  耽誤拍攝進度 )
Now, that can put an undue burden on production
因為這樣  使得我有一周不能工作
because now maybe I can't work for a week.
所以  克裡夫就要幫忙分擔這個責任
So Cliff here is meant to help carry the load.
你會這樣形容你的工作嗎  克裡夫?
Is that how you'd describe your job, Cliff?
什麼  分擔他的責任嗎?  對啊  差不多是這樣
What, carrying his load? Yeah, that's about right.
下星期請和我一起造訪「迪克·范·戴克秀」的現場
Join me next week on the set of The Dick Van Dyke Show,
我會訪問搞笑藝人  莫雷·阿斯特達姆和蘿絲·瑪莉
where I'll be talking to comical cutups, Morey Amsterdam and Rose Marie.
我是艾倫·金凱德  在好萊塢跟您說再會
Till then, this is Allen Kincade signing off from Hollywood.
# 93 KHJ #
# Yeah, my man #
# All right #
# Hey! #
# Oh, you're looking good, baby #
我好想你
Hi. I missed you.
# I wanna tell you a story  I wanna tell you a story #
# Every man oughta know #
黑色箱子  有花的
The black one. And the flowers.
# If you want a little lovin' If you want a little lovin' #
有花的  愛娃
Flowers, Ava, flowers.
還有小的那個
And there's the small one.
我能驗票嗎?
Can I see your tickets?
乖狗狗
Oh, good boy.
# If you just treat her right now  If you just treat her right now #
# Hey, hey, hey, hey! #
# Hey! #
# All right! #
# Hey, yeah! #
# Hey! #
# Hey, all right! #
# Well, it's all right! #
# Hey! #
# Hey, hey, hey! #
# Oh, work it now, one time! #
# Ooow! #
# You're too much, baby, all right #
# Hey! #
( 1969年2月8日 星期六 )
謀殺  復仇和充滿激情的陰謀
Murder, revenge and passionate intrigue.
維爾娜·麗絲主演的洛城電視臺劇集
Virna Lisi stars in the Los Angeles television premiere
《愛恨欲》
of Love, Hate and Desire
週六9點播出
Saturday at 9:00 on KHJ-TV 9.
吉娜  吉娜  吉娜
Gina, Gina, Gina.
迷霧亮光中的臉龐
The face in the misty light.
- 您好  施沃茲先生  - 你好  吉娜
- Hello, Mr. Schwarz. - Hello, Gina.
我和一位帥氣牛仔有約
I, uh... I have a meeting with a very handsome cowboy man.
他在吧台等您
He's waiting for you in the bar.
啊
Ah.
哇...
Well...
我才剛他媽追完瑞克·達爾頓的電影
since I just finished watching a Rick Dalton fucking film festival,
所以我知道你是誰  握個手吧
I think I know who you are. Put it there.
這是我的榮幸  舒沃茲先生  謝謝你的關注
Well, it's my pleasure, Mr. Schwartz. And thank you for taking an interest.
施  不是舒
Schwarz, not Schwartz.
真他媽的  我很抱歉
Ah. G-goddamn it to hell. I'm-I'm sorry about that.
- 這是我的榮幸  施沃茲先生  - 叫我馬文
- It's my pleasure, Mr. Schwarz. - Call me Marvin.
馬文  叫我瑞克
Marvin, call me Rick.
- 瑞克?  - 嗯
- Rick? - Yeah.
- 那是你兒子嗎?  - 兒子?
- Oh, is that your son? - My son?
不是啦  是我的特技替身  克裡夫·布茲
No, that's my stunt double, Cliff Booth. Yeah.
很高興認識你
Good to meet you.
我們合作了最後兩季的《賞金律法》
We've worked together since the last two seasons of Bounty Law.
- 是嗎?  - 我的車在修  所以他載我來
- Yeah? - My car's in the shop, so he gave me a ride.
他媽的胡扯
That's a big fucking lie.
瑞克被開太多酒駕罰單  所以駕照被吊銷了
Rick got his driver's license taken away for too many drunk-driving tickets.
- 克裡夫現在載他到處跑  - 操
- Cliff drives him everywhere now. - Oh, fuck.
聽起來是個好朋友
Well, sounds like a good friend.
- 我儘量  - 嗯
- I try. - Mm.
我要替我太太瑪麗·艾麗絲向你致意
I wanna send you greetings from my wife, Mary Alice Schwarz.
噢  真好
Oh, well, that's nice.
多謝
Thanks a lot.
昨晚我們在放映室  連看兩部瑞克·達爾頓的電影
We had a Rick Dalton double feature in our screening room last night.
噢  我感覺既欣慰又尷尬
Oh, well, that's both flattering and-and embarrassing.
你呢?
What'd you see?
35毫米膠捲的《譚納》
Thirty-five mm prints of Tanner
和《麥克拉斯基的14拳》
and The Fourteen Fists of McCluskey.
( 《麥克拉斯基的14拳》 )
( 《譚納》 )
希望這兩部瑞克·達爾頓的電影
I hope the, uh, Rick Dalton double feature
對您和夫人來說不會太痛苦
wasn't too painful for you and the... And the missus.
不  "痛苦"  別說了  怎麼會呢?
Oh, no. "Painful." Stop. What are you saying?
瑪麗·艾麗絲愛西部片
Mary Alice loves Westerns.
我們交往的時候都在看西部片
Our whole courtship, we watched Westerns.
- 你的酒  - 謝謝
- Here you go. - Thanks.
我們非常喜歡《譚納》
And we thoroughly enjoyed Tanner.
- 噢  真好  - 真正的好片
- Oh, that's nice. - It's really good.
然後呢  她去睡了
And anyway, she goes to bed.
我打開一盒哈瓦那雪茄
I open up a box of Havanas.
點好  倒一杯白蘭地  然後看片...
I light up, I pour myself a cognac and I watch...
《麥克拉斯基的14拳》
The Fourteen Fists of McCluskey.
真是好片
What a picture.
- 真是好片  - 是啊  好電影
- What a picture. - Good picture, yeah.
太開心了
That is so much fun.
那些開槍掃射的場景
All the shooting.
你知道  我喜歡那套  殺殺殺
I love that stuff. You know, the killing.
很多殺戮戲
A lot of killing. Lot of killing, yeah.
各位  我們計畫將兵力回檔...
Now, gentlemen, the plan is, we reverse our forces
然後將盟軍逼回海上
and drive the Allies back into the sea!
天才
Genius.
裝甲師一到
Panzer divisions come in,
我們就能痛擊敵軍
and we drive them here to the ocean.
他們必會戰敗
They'll be up against the wall.
- 他們無路可逃  - 對
- They will have nowhere to go. - Yes.
這個計畫...
This is the spot...
艾赫曼
Hermann!
打開布幕
Open the curtains.
有人點火烤酸菜嗎?
Anybody order fried sauerkraut?
燃燒吧  納粹渾球
Burn, you Nazi bastards! Ha-ha-ha!
操作噴火器的是你  對吧?
That's you operating the flamethrower, isn't it?
當然是我了  沒錯
Oh, you bet your sweet ass it was. Yeah.
- 是你?  - 我告訴你  那武器超變態的
- It was you? - Yeah. And let me tell you, that-that's one shit-fuck crazy weapon
你可不想站錯邊
y-y-you do not wanna be on the wrong side of.
天呐
Boy, oh, boy.
我花了兩個星期排練
You know, I practiced with that dragon, uh,
每天練三小時
three hours a day for two weeks.
並不是只想拍出好畫面
Not just because I wanted to look good in the picture,
我打從心裡害怕  真的  我恨死這鬼東西了
but because I was... I was shit-scared of the thing, to be honest.
他奶奶的  把納粹烤到酥脆
Mike fucking Lewis! Crisping them Nazis to hell!
靠  實在是...
Oh, shit, that's...
太燙了
All right, that's too hot.
有辦法調整熱度嗎?
Anything we can do about that heat?
- 瑞克  這是噴火器  - 好吧
- Rick, it's a flamethrower. - Yeah.
我今天提早到辦公室
So I came to the office early today,
看了兩集16毫米膠捲的《賞金律法》
and I watched two episodes of Bounty Law on 16 mm.
裘帝·簡尼斯
Jody Janice,
因在懷俄明州偷牛被通緝
wanted for cattle rustling in the state of Wyoming,
獎金425美元  不論死活
$425 dead or alive.
而你帶他來這裡領賞
And you brought him here to collect.
我根本不知道這裡是哪裡
I don't even know where here is.
只是這裡最近
It was just the closest place.
在城外大約五英里處撞見他
Caught up with him about five miles outside of town.
那麼  賞金殺手
So, bounty killer,
這城鎮叫作簡尼斯鎮
the name of this town is Janicetown.
你殺的那孩子...
And that boy you killed...
是裘帝·簡尼斯
was Jody Janice.
他是納森·麥斯威爾·簡尼斯少校的小兒子
He was the baby boy of Major Nathin Maxwell Janice.
哼
Hmm.
誰是納森·麥斯威爾·簡尼斯少校?
Who's Major Nathin Maxwell Janice?
這個嘛  當他到這的時候
Well, I'll be sure and introduce you
我會介紹你們認識
when he gets here.
《賞金律法》
Bounty Law.
瑞克·達爾頓主演
Starring Rick Dalton.
然後檔案室幾個愛搞笑的傢伙
Then a couple of the jokers over in archival sent over
送來一份小禮物  有你的表演
a kinescope of a little treat featuring you.
# 有架老鋼琴 #
# There's an old piano #
# 他們猛彈它  在綠門後面 #
# And they play it hot behind the green door #
# 不知道他們在做什麼#
# Don't know what they're doing #
# 但他們笑得很開心  在綠門後面 #
# But they laugh a lot behind the green door #
# 真希望他們讓我進去 #
# Wish they'd let me in #
# 我就會知道  綠門後面是什麼 #
# So I can find out what's behind the green door #
所以過去幾年
So, uh, you've been doing guest shots
你一直在電視單元劇客串
on episodic TV shows the last couple of years?
對啊  我正在拍哥倫比亞廣播公司的試播劇
Yeah. Yeah. I'm doing a pilot f-for CBS right now.
叫作《蘭瑟》  我演惡棍
It's called... It's called Lancer. I play the heavy.
我演了羅恩·伊萊的《泰山》
Did a, ahem, Ron Ely Tarzan.
《巨人家園》 《青蜂俠》
I did a Land of the Giants. Green Hornet.
我演出《英雄馬丁》
I did that show, uh...
和史考特·布郎那小子主演
Bingo Martin with that kid Scott Brown. Yeah.
還有這周日播映的《聯邦調查局》
And I got a F.B.I. that-that airs this Sunday.
你總是演壞人?
You, um... You always play the bad guy on these shows?
- 對啊  - 是的
- Y-yeah. Mm-hm. - Yeah.
在最後都會有打鬥戲?
So, and they have a fight scene at the end of them?
不  不...
Well, not... Not...
《巨人家園》和《聯邦調查局》沒有
Not Land of the Giants or F.B.I.,
- 但其它的有  - 而你打輸了?
- but the rest, yeah. Yeah. - And you lose in the fight?
對啊  當然  我是惡棍嘛
Yeah. Yeah, of course. I'm... I'm the heavy.
噢  那是電視臺耍的老把戲
Oh, that's an old trick pulled by the networks.
以《英雄馬丁》舉例好了
Now, you take Bingo Martin, for example.
- 嗯哼  - 對吧?
- Mm-hm. - Right?
史考特·布郎是個新人
So you got a new guy like Scott Brown.
得建立他的正面形象  對吧?
You wanna build up his bona fides, right?
- 所以就從被停播的劇集裡  找人來演壞蛋  - 哼
- So you hire a guy from a canceled show to play the heavy. - Hmm.
然後在最後的打鬥戲  英雄戰勝反派
Then at the end of the show, when they fight, it's hero besting heavy.
但觀眾看到的卻是
But what the audience sees
英雄馬丁教訓傑克·卡希爾
is Bingo Martin whipping Jake Cahill's ass.
- 嗯哼  - 你懂嗎?
- Uh-huh. - You see?
然後下個星期  換羅恩·伊萊
Then next week, it's Ron Ely.
再下個星期  換成羅伯特·康瑞德
And next week, it's Bob Conrad,
他穿著緊身褲扁你
wearing his tight pants, kicking your ass.
對
Yeah.
然後  你不斷在電視臺劇集客串幾年
Now, in another couple of years, playing punching bag
卻只能做青年偶像的人肉沙包
to every swinging dick new to the network,
這可是會在心理上
that's gonna have a psychological effect
影響觀眾對你的印象
on how the audience perceives you.
我懂
Right.
所以  瑞克
So, Rick,
下星期換誰扁你?
who's gonna kick the shit out of you next week?
《曼尼斯》? 《紳士密令》?
Mannix? The Man from U.N.C.I.E.?
《女孩密令》?
The Girl from U.N.C.I.E.?
《蝙蝠俠與羅賓》如何?
How about Batman and Robin?
呯  砰
Ping. Pow.
咚  沖
Choom. Zoom.
你倒下了
Down goes you.
你的男一號生涯也起不來了
Down goes your career as a leading man.
或者  你可以去羅馬主演西部片
Or do you go to Rome and star in Westerns
然後他媽的打勝仗
and win fucking fights?
停車票
Ticket, señor?
好了  怎麼回事  搭檔?
All right, what's the matter, partner?
嗯...
Well...
完了  老友  我過氣了
it's official, old buddy. I'm a has-been.
什麼意思?  那傢伙對你說了什麼?
What are you talking about? What did that guy tell you?
他對我說了該死的實話
He told me the goddamn truth, is what he told me.
- 好了  - 靠
- Oh. Whoa. - Oh, shit.
- 嘿  - 對不起  對不起
- Hey. - I'm sorry about that. Sorry about that.
來  戴上
Here. Put these on.
別在墨西哥人面前哭
Don't cry in front of the Mexicans.
- 他媽的  - 你怎麼這麼激動呢?
- Son of a bitch. - What's got you so upset, man?
如果眼見職業生涯結束不值得哭泣
Well, if coming face-to-face with the failure that is your career ain't worth crying about,
那我他媽不知道該為什麼哭
then I don't know what the fuck is.
剛剛那傢伙拒絕你?
Right. That guy in there turn you down?
不  他想幫我拿到那義大利電影的工作
No. He wants to help me get into Italian movies.
那有什麼不好?
Then what's the problem?
我得拍他媽的義大利電影
I gotta do Italian goddamn movies!
- 那他媽的就是不好  - 行了
- That's the fucking problem! - Come on.
他媽的狗屁  我在大庭廣眾哭又沒關係
Fucking bullshit! It doesn't matter whether I cry in public.
反正沒人記得我他媽的是誰
Nobody remembers who the fuck I am anyway, huh?
司法廳的律師
At the Hall of Justice here.
將為殺害甘迺迪總統的疑犯辯護
The defense will try to prove the killing of Kennedy
- 稱其患有精神疾病  - 操
- was the product of a sick mind. - Fuck!
- 嘿  走吧  - 克裡夫  帶我回家
- Thank you. Hey, let's go. - Take me home, Cliff.
快帶我回家
Come on, take me home.
最早下週三
As early as next Wednesday.
最新報導  超過一千名共產黨士兵
More than 1,000 Communists dead are reported
在南越的新戰役中死亡
in new, large-scale fighting in South Vietnam.
美軍的傷亡人數...
U.S. losses are said to be...
真好  夥計
That's swell, man.
他媽的死嬉皮
Fucking hippie motherfuckers.
炮火猛烈攻擊了基地
And bases with rockets and mortar fire.
尼克森總統飛往歐洲途中
As President Nixon was flying to Europe,
他通過無線電收到了戰報
he received details of that fighting by radio.
# 永遠即永恆 #
# Always is always forever #
# 只要團結一心 #
# As long as one is one #
# 心中只為父親 #
# Inside yourself, for your father #
# 團結就能一心  團結就能一心 #
# All is one, all is one, all is one #
# 是時候放棄私愛 #
# It's time we put our love behind you #
# 幻想只是夢一場 #
# The illusion has been just a dream #
# 通過死之谷  我就找到你 #
# The Valley of Death and I'll find you #
# 在陽光普照之時 #
# Now is when on a sunshine beam #
熱狗麵包
Hot dog buns!
# 他們一定會看見 #
# For sure they shall surely see #
# 沒有衣服  沒有眼淚  沒有饑餓 #
# No clothing, no tears, no hunger #
# 你會明白  你會明白 #
# You shall see, you shall see, you shall see #
# 永遠即永恆#
# Always is always forever #
# 只要團結一心#
# As long as one is one #
# 心中只為父親 #
# Inside yourself, for your father #
# 團結就能一心  團結就能一心 #
# All is one, all is one, all is one #
花了五年往上爬
Five years of ascent. Pfft.
十年來沒有長進
Ten years of-of-of treading water.
現在開始跌入谷底
And now a race to the bottom. Heh.
聽著  我從來沒有什麼職業可談
Look, I never had much of a career to speak of,
所以我不敢說我懂你的感受
so I can't say I really know how you feel.
什麼話?  你是我的特技替身
What are you talking about? You're my stunt double.
拜託  靠
Come on, now. Shit.
瑞克  我是你的司機  幫你打雜
Rick, I'm your driver, man. I'm-I'm your gofer.
我不是在抱怨  老兄  我喜歡開車載你到處跑
I'm not complaining, man. I like driving you around.
我喜歡在家整理環境
I like doing shit around the house
你出門時  我在好萊塢山莊幫你顧家
and house-sitting in the Hollywood Hills when you're gone.
但我好一陣子沒當全職替身了
But I haven't been a full-time stuntman for a while now,
從我的角度來看
and from where I'm standing,
去羅馬主演電影
going to Rome to star in movies does not sound
不像你想的比死還糟糕
like the fate worse than death that you seem to think it is.
拜託  你看過義大利西部片嗎?
Come on, now. You ever seen an-an Italian Western, huh?
爛透了  他媽的鬧劇
They're awful. It's a fucking farce.
你看過幾部?  一部?  兩部?
Yeah, how many you seen? One? Two?
我看夠了  好嗎?  沒人愛看"義大利通心粉式西部片"
I've seen enough, all right? Nobody likes Spaghetti Westerns.
這是唐·斯蒂爾音樂秀  請欣賞西蒙和嘉芬克爾演唱的歌曲
Sweet. The Real Don Steele, with Simon and Garfunkel hit,
"羅賓遜夫人"
Mrs. Robinson.
# 獻給你 #
# And here's to you #
比爾·考斯比  弗蘭克·辛納特拉和他的女兒南茜
Frank Sinatra, Bill Cosby and Nancy Sinatra
以及湯姆·史莫勒斯將會主持音樂節
with Tom Smothers as master of ceremonies will appear in concert
( 天堂大道 )
他皮膚上的刺青很恐怖
There are fearful pictures on his skin.
但最恐怖的是他靈魂內的刺青
But the most fearful thing is tattooed on his soul.
《繪圖人》
The Illustrated Man.
雷·布萊德伯裡的超自然傑作
Ray Bradbury's masterpiece of the supernatural.
一部超乎想像的奇幻恐怖大片
An incredible journey to the outer limits of imagination.
媽的  老兄  留在洛杉磯
Oh, hell, man, stay in I.A.
專心拍下一出的試播劇
Give it what fer next pilot season.
不  不...
Nah, nah. I'm... I'm...
我現在太沒安全感  接不到新的試播劇
I'm too insecure now to score come pilot season.
況且  幕寶對我沒有好評價
Screen Gems ain't gonna have nothing good to say about me.
- 你知道的  - 狗屁  你拍過《賞金律法》
- You know that. - Shit. You made Bounty Law.
因為最後一季的矛盾  沒人會原諒我的
Nobody's gonna forgive me for that last season.
- 不管我做什麼...  - 啊...
- No matter what I do... - Ah...
我永遠會是那個害《賞金律法》停播的爛咖
I'm always gonna be the horse's ass that got Bounty Law canceled
只因為我想要成為紅不起來的電影明星
because I wanted some fucking rinky-dink movie career.
- 湯姆  我朋友啊  - 我見過他?
- Tom. My friend. - I met him?
不  你沒見過
No, you haven't met him.
我是說你不會見到他  因為我覺得你不會喜歡他
You won't meet him because I don't think you'd like him.
- 為什麼?  - 呃...
- Why? - Well...
四個男人在尋找
Four men on a search
- 那是玩笑  - 他們被嚇到了
- Don't even joke. - A joke? But they're scared.
我行我素
Living his own way.
搜尋
Searching.
探索
Discovering.
頭號人物
Numero Uno.
新款男士香水
The new thing in colognes for men.
世界上只有四種基本的男性氣味
In all the world, there're only four basic masculine scents.
哇靠
Holy shit. Heh.
那是波蘭斯基
That was Polanski.
羅曼·波蘭斯基
That was Roman Polanski.
他住那裡一個月了
He's lived there for a month now.
我還是第一次看見他
First time I seen him. Ha-ha-ha.
靠  真該死
Holy shit. Goddamn it.
我都是怎麼說的?
What do I always say?
在這城裡最重要的是
Most important thing in this town is,
當你發達了  你買房  不用租的
when you're making money, you buy a house in town. You don't rent.
艾迪·歐布萊恩教我的
Eddie O'Brien taught me that.
有好萊塢房產表示你住下來了
Hollywood real estate means you live here.
不只是來訪  不只是經過
You're not just visiting, not just passing through.
而是他媽的住在這裡
You fucking live here.
我現在慘兮兮  但我隔壁住著誰?
Here I am flat on my ass, and who I got living next door to me?
他媽的《羅斯瑪麗的嬰兒》的導演耶
The director of Rosemary's fucking Baby, that's who.
波蘭斯基可能是全世界最搶手的導演
Polanski, the hottest director in town right now, probably the world.
他媽的是我鄰居
He's my next-door neighbor.
靠  我是說  誰知道會有這種事?
I mean, shit. I mean, who knows what could happen?
開個泳池派對  我可能就會主演波蘭斯基的電影了
I could... I could be one pool party away f-from starring in a new Polanski movie.
所以你現在覺得好多了?
So you're feeling better now?
噢  對啊  抱歉鬧那麼大
Aw, yeah, yeah. Sorry about all that.
墨鏡還我
Give me my glasses back.
來拿啊  王八蛋
Oh, come get them, fucker. Come...
好啦  拳王  別緊張
All right, all right, Audie Murphy, relax.
- 給你  - 還有別的事需要我嗎?
- There you go. - You need me for anything else?
不了  我要背明天的臺詞
Nah, nah, nah. I got a lot of lines to learn for tomorrow.
- 靠  - 好的
- Shit. All right. - All right.
- 我累死了  回家去  - 好的
- I'm gonna get my carcass on home. - All right.
- 明早7點15分  - 7點15分
- All right, 7:15 a.m. - Seven-fifteen.
- 在門外等?  - 在門外等
- Out the door. - Out the door.
- 我在車裡等  - 好  到時候見
- In the car. - All right, see you then.
# Brrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrr...uck #
# Chuck a-chuck-chuck #
# Little darlin' do not let a tear #
# Fall-a from your ey-ey-ey-ey-eye #
# Well she wrote me the letter #
# Said that she couldn't live #
# Without me no more #
# Listen to me mister #
# Please don't you ever #
# My baby once more #
# Anyway #
# Give a listen #
# 'Cause I was born lonely #
# Down by the riverside #
# Learned to spin fortune wheels #
# And throw dice #
# I was just thirteen #
# When I had to leave home #
# Knew I couldn't stick around #
# I had to roam #
# Ain't good lookin' #
# But you know I ain't shy #
# Ain't afraid to look you girl #
# Hey, in the eye #
# So if you need some lovin' #
# Now, full o' jitterbugs from Pico Rivera, baby #
# I'ma come on loose for ya #
# Hey, Hector! Your momma lookin' for you #
( 範·奈斯 汽車影院 )
( 正在放映《水泥中的女士》 )
( 即將放映《美麗的毒藥》 )
# Oh, yeah, boy #
如果你還沒喝過杯根啤酒
Well, if you haven't tried one with Mug Root Beer,
現在就試試
start droolin' now.
老牌啤酒  新式包裝  味道爽口
Mug, old-fashioned root beer in the new twist top bottle.
# KHJ Boss hit bomb! #
# This is the house that Jack built, y'all #
# Remember this house! #
哈囉
Hello, coming in. Hello. # MacArthur Park is melting in the dark  MacArthur Park is melting in the dark #
親愛的  嗯  嗯
Hello, darling. Hello. Mm. Mm. # All the sweet, green icing  All the sweet, green icing #
來嘛
Come here.# Flowing down  Flowing down #
甜心
Hello, sweetheart.
你今天過得如何?
Mm. How was your day? Hmm?
等著看我帶了什麼給你
Wait till you see what I got for you.
Wait until you see what I got for you.
看我帶了什麼給你
Look what I got for you.
會嚇死你噢
Gonna blow your mind, man.
過來  過來
Come here. Come here.
嗒嗒嗒  噢
Ta, ta, ta. Oh!
( 狼牙牌狗糧 )
( 口味多樣  富含維他命D )
( 給惡狗的好食物 )
( 浣熊味  老鼠味 )
( 《洋場私探》 )
它是數字遊戲
It's numbers game.
它是狂野遊戲
It's a wild game.
閣樓裡三個女人
Take 3... 3 in the Attic.
這三個女人
These three.
托比  性福的充實生活
Tobey, one full of life.
你是在哀怨嗎?
Was that a whine?
我說過什麼?  哀怨就沒得吃
What did I tell you about whining? You whine, you don't eat.
我會把這東西丟掉  我不想  但我會
I will throw this shit in the trash. I don't wanna, but I will.
懂嗎?
You understand?
好
All right.
# That's all very well, but not with my daughter, you don't #
( 電視指南 )
我等到酒吧打烊
I waited at the bar till closing time,
但他從沒回來
but he never came back.
佩姬  發生了什麼事?
Okay, Peggy, what happened?
我不知道  一切都好好的
I don't know. Everything was fine.
我們在家吃晚餐
We had dinner at my house.
之後  你知道的
And afterwards, you know,
- 我在洗碗  - 噠噠
- while I was doing the dishes, - Tsk, tsk.
他和托比在玩
He and Tobey played.
然後在俱樂部裡  蓋伯本來好好的
And then, at the club, Gabe was doing great.
然後  轟  突然變了
Then, wham, a sudden change.
你知道音樂家的德性  像貓一樣喜怒無常
You know how musicians are. They're temperamental cats.
- 誰知道他怎麼了?  - 說得好
- Who knows what got into him? - Yeah.
瑞克·達爾頓試鏡錄音
Rick Dalton rehearsal tape starting in
倒數  五  四  三  二  一
five, four, three, two, one.
佩比  給我滾去顧吧台  我有客人
Pepe, get your behind behind that bar! I got a guest.
強尼說  西班牙文嘰哩呱啦
Johnny says... Spanish, Spanish, Spanish.
豆子好吃嗎?
How's the beans?
我吃過更難吃的
I've had worse.
強尼說  西班牙文
Johnny says... Spanish.
敬酒
A toast.
敬我的妻子和我所有的情人
To my wife and all my sweethearts.
願她們永遠不會碰面
May they never meet.
馬德里先生  願意來我這桌  陪我招待客人嗎?
Señor Madrid, care to join me at my table where I entertain my guests?
我很樂意  達可塔先生
I would be delighted, Monsieur Dakota.
酒瓶帶著
Take the bottle with you.
然後佩比走過來
And Pepe comes over.
嘿  你那位拉小提琴的辣妹女兒去哪了?
Hey, where's that chili pepper daughter of yours with the fiddle?
她睡了
She's asleep.
叫醒她啊
Well, wake her the heck up, get her down here
讓她帶上琴和弓  下來娛樂我的客人
with her fiddle and her bow, and entertain my guests.
是  先生
Sí, señor,
但我求你  這次別傷害她  好嗎?
but please don't hurt her this time, I beg you.
我不會傷害她  我只是要她拉琴
I ain't gonna hurt her. Just want her to play the fiddle.
快去找她  說我會賞她一大枚五元金幣
Fetch her and tell her I'll give her a fat $5 gold piece,
她得用力死命地拉琴
she play her little chili pepper heart out.
所以  強尼  你還聽過我的哪些事情?
So, Johnny, what else you heard about me?
我聽說你把蘭瑟逼得很緊
I heard you're pushing Lancer pretty hard,
但蘭瑟有錢
but Lancer has money.
總有一天  他會找幫手反擊
At some point, he's gonna hire some guns and push back.
- 抱歉  - 沒關係
- Oops, sorry. - It's okay.
我替你開門
I'll open the door for you.
你看起來很美
You look good.
天使之城  晚上9點  我會陪你到淩晨5點
9:00 in the City of Angels! Your brother here, 10 to 5.
史蒂夫·麥奎因也會去那裡
I think Steve's gonna be there too.
- 是嗎?  - 是的
- Oh, yeah? - Oh, yeah.
嗨起來
So rock on!
# Na na na na #
# Na na na, na na na #
# I got a certain little girl she's on my mind #
# No doubt about it she looks so fine #
# She's the best girl that I ever had #
# Sometimes she's gonna make me feel so bad #
# Na na na na #
# Na na na, na na na #
# Hush, hush #
# I thought I heard her calling my name now #
# She broke my heart but I love her just the same now #
# Hush, hush #
- 噢  看呐  他們來了
Oh, look. They're here.
# Thought I heard her calling my name now  Thought I heard her calling my name now #
( 花花公子莊園 )
[PLAYBOY MANSION]
# Hush, hush Hush, hush #
# I need her loving and I'm not to blame now #
( 史蒂夫·麥奎因  米雪·菲力浦斯  傑·塞布林 )
歡迎光臨花花公子莊園  波蘭斯基先生
Welcome to the Playboy Mansion, Mr. Polanski.
嗨  你好嗎  寶貝?
Hey, how are you doing, baby?
嘿  你好嗎?
Hey! Heh. How are you?
# The tears that you're starting to cry are no good #
# Cause you know I loved you #
# Much better than anybody would #
# And it was understood #
蓋絲
Oh, Cass!
# That I wouldn't be That I wouldn't be #
# Staying around a long time #
# You knew that someday #
# I'd wake up, baby #
# And I'd find #
耶
Yeah!
# Somebody further down the line  Somebody further down the line #
# I'm the son of a lovin' man #
耶  寶貝
Yeah, baby!
# My daddy told me My daddy told me #
# Get you all the loving you can #
- 耶  唔  唔
Yeah! Whoo! Whoo!
# And I can  And I can # -
# 'Cause I, I'm the son #
# I'm the son, son #
# I'm the son, son I'm the son, son #
耶
Oh, yeah.
# Son of a loving man  Son of a loving man #
# My daddy before me told me #
# That his daddy before him told him #
# Never wait around #
# And never settle down #
# 'Cause there are too many women #
# Who will hold on tight #
# To a loving man who will come along #
# And treat them right #
# But you got to leave with the morning light #
我要跟你說個故事
I'm gonna tell you a story.
她  跟他訂過婚
She was engaged to him.
然後她飛去英國...
Then she flew to the UK...
跟他拍電影
to make a film with him,
跟他解除婚約  然後嫁給了他
and broke off her engagement with him and married him.
最後他們搬去洛杉磯
Then they moved to Los Angeles,
三個人從此變得形影不離
and the three of them have been inseparable.
真的假的?
Really?
這算哪一招?
What's up?
傑愛戀著莎朗  就這招
Jay loves Sharon, that's what's up.
- 嗯  - 而他知道...
- Mm. - And he knows...
跟上帝創造小小綠蘋果一樣肯定...
as sure as God made little green apples...
總有一天  那波蘭渾球會搞砸
( 波蘭渾球: 羅曼·波蘭斯基 )
that one of these days, that Polish prick's gonna fuck things up,
到時候  傑就會陪在她身邊
and when he does, Jay's gonna be there.
嗯  有件事是肯定的
Well, one thing's for sure.
是嗎?
Yeah?
是什麼?
What's that?
莎朗絕對有固定菜色
Sharon absolutely has a type.
可愛  不高  有才華
Cute, short, talented guys
看起來像12歲的男孩子
who look like 12-year-old boys.
是啊
Yeah.
我從來就沒希望
I never stood a chance.
# I, I'm a son #
# I'm a son, son I'm a son, son #
# I'm a son, son #
# Son of a loving man #
# I'm the son of a loving man #
# My daddy told me #
# Get you all the loving you can #
( 1969年2月9日  星期日 )
去死啦  薩博斯汀
Argh. Fuck you, Dr. Sapirstein.
# Tanya #
# From Malibu to Miami #
# You'll tan like you're in Waikiki #
# Get Tanya #
我們到了
- Oh, here we are. # Get Tanya  Get Tanya #
# Robert W. Morgan #
把那些道具都弄走
Tell transpo! Gonna need to move all that out!
稍等
Just a sec. Hold on, guys.
走吧
Go ahead.
你儘管跟他談談
You can talk to him. Just talk to him.
- 把一切處理好  - 嘿
- Get that set in place. - Hey.
昨晚大風把我的電視天線吹壞了
Ahem. I think the wind blew down my TV antenna last night,
所以我在浪費時間化妝更衣的時候
so while I piss-fart around with wardrobe,
你介意回家修嗎?
you mind going home and fixing it?
可以啊
I can.
你今天會跟特技領班提到我嗎?
You talk to the stunt gaffer about me today?
這樣我才會知道這星期要不要工作
That way I'll know if I'm working this week or not.
這個嘛  我一直想告訴你
Yeah. Ahem. I've been meaning to tell you.
這次的領班是蘭迪的死黨
The guy who gaffs this, he's best friends with Randy,
是《青蜂俠》劇組的領班
the gaffer from The Green Hornet...
所以其實提了也沒用
so there ain't no point.
如果你沒有別的需要  收工時我會來接你
If you don't need me, I'll pick you up at wrap.
我不需要你  今天不用
I don't need you. Not today.
回家修我的天線  隨便你要幹嘛  收工後見
Go home, fix my antenna, do whatever. See you at wrap.
喂
Hey!
你是最厲害的瑞克·達爾頓  不要忘了
You're Rick fucking Dalton. Don't you forget it.
嘿
Hey, hey.
老兄  我是瑞克·達爾頓
Hey, buddy, I'm Rick Dalton.
你知道我該去哪裡嗎?
You know where I'm supposed to go?
他們在化妝車上等你
They're waiting for you in the makeup trailer.
化妝車在哪?
Where's the makeup trailer?
從你剛過來的地方右轉
Straight back the way you came, hard right.
天呐
Oh, my God.
瑞克·達爾頓
Rick Dalton.
山姆·沃納梅克
Sam Wanamaker.
嘿  山姆  抱歉手濕濕的
Hey, Sam. Sorry about the wet hand.
沒關係  尤·伯連納也是這樣
Oh, don't worry. I'm used to it with Yul.
我只是要讓你知道  是我選你來演的
I want you to know, I'm the one who cast you.
你加入演出我高興死了
And I couldn't be more delighted you're doing this.
噢  謝謝你  山姆
Oh, well, thank you, Sam.
我很感謝  這是個好角色
I... I appreciate it. It's a good part.
的確是  你見過主角吉姆·史塔奇了嗎?
Yeah, it is. Have you met Jim Stacy, the series lead?
還沒有
Uh, not yet, no. No.
你們倆一起肯定會超勁爆
Well, you guys are going to be dynamite together.
嗯  聽起來很刺激
Mm. Mm. Well, it sounds exciting.
- 對啊  精彩得不得了  - 嗯
- Yeah, lightning in a bottle. - Mm.
- 你見過髮型化妝師桑尼雅嗎?  - 嗨
- Now, you met Sonya, makeup and hair? - Hi.
- 這位是服裝師瑞貝卡  - 你好
- And this is Rebekka, who does costumes. - Hello.
- 嗨  - 你好
- Hi. - Howdy.
聽好  我要給凱勒全新的造型  我不要那種西部裝扮
I want a whole new look for Caleb. I don't want this Western costumed
像《大峽谷》和《牧野風雲》中上世紀的造型
the way they costumed The Big Valley and Bonanza for the last decade.
我要反映時代精神的服裝
I want a zeitgeist flair to the costumes.
我的意思是  不要搞錯時代
I mean, nothing anachronistic,
但1869年和1969年有什麼共通點?
but where does 1869 and 1969 meet?
尤其是你  凱勒
Especially when it comes to you, Caleb.
嗯
Mm. Mm.
首先  我要他有鬍子
First off, I want to give him a mustache.
像薩帕塔那樣大把下垂的鬍鬚
A big, droopy, Zapata-like mustache.
還有  他的夾克  我要他穿嬉皮夾克
Now, about his jacket. I want to give him a hippie jacket.
他可以今晚穿著走進倫敦濃霧的那種
Something he could wear into the London Fog tonight
看起來像是最潮的傢伙
and look like the hippest guy in the room.
酷  我們有卡斯特鹿皮夾克  袖子上滿滿的裝飾
Far out. We got a Custer jacket. Fringes all down the arm.
現在是褐色  但我會染成深棕色
It's tan now, but I dye it dark brown,
今晚就可以穿上走日落大道
he could hit the Strip in it tonight.
這就對了  好姑娘
That's my girl. Heh.
- 現在  瑞克  關於你的頭髮  - 噢  我的頭髮怎麼了?
- Now, Rick, about your hair. - What about my hair?
- 我要不一樣的髮型  - 什麼?
- I want to go with a different hairstyle. - Huh. What?
比較有嬉皮風的
Something more hippie-ish.
你要我看起來像個嬉皮?
You want me to look like a hippie?
這個嘛  不要想是嬉皮  比較像是"地獄天使飆車幫"
Well, think less hippie, more... Hells Angel!
- 山姆...  - 聽著...
- Right. Say, Sam... - Get me the...
山姆  山姆...
Sam. Sam, uh...
如果你把我打扮成四不像
if you got me covered up in all this... this junk, uh,
觀眾怎麼會知道是我?
how's the audience gonna know it's me?
- 我不希望他們知道  - 嗯
- I hope they don't. - Mm.
我不要他們看到傑克·卡希爾
I don't want them to see Jake Cahill.
我要他們看見凱勒
I want them to see Caleb.
我是找你來演電影  瑞克
I hired you to be an actor, Rick.
不是來當電視劇的牛仔  你值得更好的發展
Not a TV cowboy. You're better than that.
( 《戰鬥》 KTTV電視臺 )
( 周日1點至2點播出 )
# Run to me #
# And the heavenly fragrance that clings #
# It's Heaven Sent #
# Suddenly #
# You're an imp wearing angel's wings #
# In Heaven Sent #
# Suddenly #
# You are all the things that you want to be #
# A little bit naughty but heavenly #
# In Heaven Sent #
# Kentucky woman #
# She shines with her own kind of light #
# Seems this world's #
# Got you down #
# Your feelin' bad vibrations frown #
# Well, open your eyes, girl #
# Look at me #
# I'm gonna show you how it ought to be #
# We're gonna have a good thing #
# Such a good thing, baby #
# And when your world #
# Don't seem just right #
# And life's gettin' you uptight #
# You can change that wrong to right #
我一直想告訴你
I've been meaning to tell you,
這次的領班是蘭迪的死黨
the guy who gaffs this, he's best friends with Randy,
是《青蜂俠》的領班
the gaffer from The Green Hornet,
所以其實提了也沒用
so there really ain't no point.
( 《虎! 虎! 虎! 》 )
嘿  蘭迪
Hey, Randy.
克裡夫
Cliff.
你還跟著瑞克嗎?
So you're still with Rick, huh?
還跟著
Still here.
- 他在裡面?  - 對啊  敲門就好
- He in there? - Yeah. Just knock.
聽著  就讓他穿上戲服  好嗎?
Look, just put him in the wardrobe, all right?
又沒關係
What's it gonna hurt?
如果你需要他  他就可以上場  好嗎?
Then if you need him, you got him, all right?
那我得和服裝部助理聊聊
But then I gotta have a conversation with that wardrobe assistant,
她實在是他媽的難搞  你別為難我...
and, man, she's a fucking bitch. I just don't... Please, I...
聽著  蘭迪  我在請你幫忙
Look, Randy, I'm asking you to help me out, man.
如果不行就不行  不要有藉口
If the answer's no, the answer's no, not no with excuses.
嘿  老兄
Hey, man.
這不是他媽的安德魯·麥拉格蘭的電影
This ain't a fucking Andy McLaglen picture, you know?
我沒那麼多錢雇用一群煙槍
I can't afford to hire a bunch of guys to smoke cigarettes
整天坐著閒聊  等著我可能給他們事做
and sit around talking to each other all day on the chance that I might use them.
我這組有四個人  瑞克
I got a four-man team here, Rick.
如果我要更多人  我得去申請許可
If I need more than that, I gotta get it approved.
你知道的  我得照顧下面的人
And, you know, I gotta look after my dudes.
嘿  如果你下面的人跟我比較合拍
Hey, and if your dudes were a better match for me,
那我就認了
I'd say, "Okay, you got me,"
但你知道不是這樣
but-but that's not the case, and you know it.
- 他跟我非常合拍  - 是啊...
- He's a great match for me. - Yeah, no...
嘿  你要對他幹什麼都可以
Hey, you could do anything you want to him.
靠  把他丟下樓  怎樣?  把他當火把燒
Shit. Throw him off a building, right? Light him on fire.
- 他媽的用車撞他  可以吧?  - 好
- Hit him with a fucking Lincoln, right? - Right.
有創意一點  幹什麼都可以  有機會他就很開心
Get creative. Do whatever you want. He's just happy for the opportunity.
- 瑞克  - 怎麼?
- Rick. - Yeah?
我不喜歡他
I don't dig him.
我不喜歡他帶來片場的氣氛
And I don't dig the vibe he brings on a set.
怎麼了  你們有什麼過節嗎?
What, is there some old beef between the two of you?
- 拜託  老兄  - 怎樣嘛?
- Oh, come on, man. - What? What?
那傢伙他媽的幹掉了他老婆
The dude killed his fucking wife.
拜託  你不會相信那種過時的八卦吧?
Come on, man. You don't believe that old shit, do you?
瑞克  我相信
Yes, Rick, I do.
我和我老婆工作  她相信
And I work with my wife, and she believes it.
她不想要那個怪咖一起共事
She doesn't want his creepy ass around.
這可能是史上最爛的天氣
You know, this is probably the shittiest weather ever.
最爛的天氣  跟最爛的人  在最爛的船上
The shittiest weather on the shittiest boat with the shittiest person.
我姐姐娜塔莉說  "他是個遜咖"
Natalie, my sister, said, "He's a loser. He's a loser."
大家都說"他是個該死的遜咖"  而我就是不信
They all said it, "He's a fucking loser," and I didn't believe them.
所以我猜我是該死的白癡
So I guess I'm the fucking idiot.
你現在不想跟我說話了?  你不想吵架?
And now you're not gonna talk to me? What, you don't feel like fighting?
我呢  他媽的超想吵架  因為我自己一個人
Well, I feel like fucking fighting because I've been up here by myself
在這他媽的爛船上待了四個小時
for four hours on this fucking shithole of a boat.
對
Yeah.
他是天殺的戰爭英雄  操
H-he's a goddamn war hero. Fuck.
非常感謝
Yeah, appreciate it.
好吧  你這爛咖  我們去服裝部吧
Okay, you fucking horse's ass. Let's get you over to wardrobe.
我讓你穿戲服
Now, I'll put you in wardrobe,
但你不做特技  我也不會付你薪水
but you don't stunt, I don't pay you.
謝謝你給我機會  蘭迪  我不會讓你失望的
Appreciate the opportunity, Randy. I won't let you down.
你知道我太太珍娜吧?
You know my wife Janet, don't you?
知道
Yeah.
離她遠一點
Steer clear of her.
我尊敬拳王阿裡  真的
Now, I admire Cassius Clay, I do.
我尊敬的是在他的體育競技裡  具有真實打鬥的成分
What I admire is, in his sport, there's an element of true combat.
當阿裡和利斯頓在拳擊場上  不是兩個運動員在做樣子
When Cassius Clay meets Sonny Liston in the ring, that's not two athletes posturing.
那是戰鬥
That's combat.
兩個人在當下試著殺掉彼此
Two men trying to kill each other right now.
如果你不擊敗他...
If you don't beat him...
他就會幹掉你
he kills you.
那不只是運動  不只是體育新聞節目
That's beyond athletics. That's beyond Wide World of Sports, you know?
那是兩個戰士在進行戰鬥  這就是我尊敬的
That's two warriors engaged in combat. That's what I admire.
在武術競賽裡  不會讓你那樣打鬥
In martial arts tournaments, they won't let you fight like that.
讓人超氣餒
It's very frustrating.
站在一個人面前  你只會全力攻擊他
You stand in front of a guy, and you just wanna let him have it. Ha!
但你不能
But you can't.
所以只能像扮家家酒一樣
So you gotta do this playacting, patty-cake version.
阿裡  桑尼·利斯頓  喬·路易士
Cassius Clay. Sonny Liston. Joe Louis.
有色人種拳擊手  不是那個打跆拳道的白人混球
The colored boxer, not that white kickboxing asshole.
他們不擇手段獲勝
They do what they need to do to win.
他們使出渾身解數擊敗對手
They unleash as much punishment as they have to to defeat the other guy.
但在武術競賽中  我用一樣的方式獲勝
But in martial arts tournaments, I do to win what they do to win.
我使出全力
I unleash all my power.
我殺人
I kill people.
如果你和阿裡對打  誰會贏?
If you fought Cassius Clay, who would win?
這個嘛  永遠不會發生
Well, that would never happen.
如果真的打  你覺得會怎麼樣?
But if you did, what do you think would happen?
我會把他打到殘廢
I'd make him a cripple.
笑死人
Hmm.
喂  你  你叫什麼名字?
Hey, you. What's your name?
- 我?  - 對  你
- Me? - Yeah, you.
我叫克裡夫
My name's Cliff.
我是瑞克·達爾頓的特技替身
I'm Rick Dalton's stunt double.
- 特技演員?  - 是啊
- Stuntman? - Yeah.
你長這麼美  當特技演員?
You know, you're kind of pretty for a stuntman.
別人也是這麼說的
That's what they tell me.
我說了什麼好笑的話嗎  特技演員?
So did I say something funny, stuntman?
- 有啊  - 有什麼好笑的?
- Yeah, you kind of did. - What's so funny?
聽著  老兄  我不想惹麻煩
Look, man, I don't want any trouble.
我只是來工作的
I'm just here to do a job.
但你在笑我說的話
But you're laughing at what I'm saying.
但我沒有說笑話
But I'm not saying anything funny.
所以  你覺得哪裡好笑?
So, what do you think is so funny?
我覺得...
What I think is...
你是人小嘴大愛吹牛
you're a little man with a big mouth and a big chip,
你無恥到以為你能碰到阿裡一根汗毛
and I think you should be embarrassed to suggest you'd be anything more
但你只配當阿裡內褲上的污漬
than a stain on the seat of Cassius Clay's trunks.
兄弟  大嘴巴的是你
Brother, you're the one with the big mouth.
我很樂意  在我所有朋友的面前讓你閉嘴
And I would really enjoy closing it, especially in front of all my friends.
但我的手是公認的致命武器
But my hands are registered as lethal weapons.
這表示  如果我們幹架
That means, we get into a fight,
我意外打死你  我會去坐牢
I accidentally kill you, I go to jail.
任何人意外打死人都要坐牢
Anybody accidentally kills anybody in a fight, they go to jail.
那叫作過失殺人
It's called manslaughter.
我認為"致命武器"這種屁話
And I think all that "lethal weapon" horseshit
只是你們這些花拳繡腿的藉口  因為你從不需要真的打鬥
is just an excuse so you dancers never have to get in a real fight.
好吧
Okay.
來場友誼賽如何?
How about a friendly contest?
不打臉
No punching in the face.
三戰兩勝
Two out of three.
看誰將對方打倒在地
Who puts who on the ground first?
不用嘗試傷害對方  只看誰先坐在地上
Nobody tries to hurt nobody, just who ends up on their butt?
好主意  加藤
That's a great idea, Kato.
布魯斯(李小龍)  那傢伙有點名氣
You know, Bruce, that guy's kind of famous.
那傢伙?
That guy?
怎麼會?
For what?
他殺了老婆還能脫罪
Killed his wife and got away with it.
那傢伙?
That guy?
就是他
That guy.
不賴嘛  加藤
Not bad, Kato.
再來
Try that again.
喂  喂  喂
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
你們他媽的在這幹嘛?
What the fuck is going on here?
喂  爛咖  他是主角
Hey, jackass, this is our series lead.
你他媽的在想什麼?
What the fuck are you thinking?
你說的對  珍娜  我很抱歉
You're right, Janet. I'm sorry about that.
你他媽的不要叫我珍娜  賤人
Don't fucking "Janet" me, you prick.
嘿  怎麼了  寶貝?
Hey. What's up, babe?
"怎麼了"咧  蘭迪  你的廢物屬下
What's up, Randy, is that your loser asshole,
這個殺妻犯在痛扁布魯斯(李小龍)
wife-killing buddy boy here was beating the shit out of Bruce.
什麼?
What?
- 嘿  蘭迪  - 克裡夫
- Hey, Randy. - Cliff.
你在幹什麼啊?
What the fuck, man?
容我說  沒人痛扁布魯斯
Let me just say, nobody beat the shit out of Bruce.
這是一場友誼賽  他根本沒碰到我
It was a friendly contest. He barely touched me.
我想那車子的凹陷和你的說法不一致
I think that dent in the car says something different.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
你他媽的對我的車做了什麼?
What the fuck did you do to my car?!
你他媽的對她的車做了什麼?
What the fuck did you do to her car?
我把這小混蛋扔過去
I threw this little prick into it,
但我不知道那是她的車
but I did not know it was her car.
衣服脫下  收拾東西  然後去死
Get the wardrobe off, get your shit, and get fucked!
- 珍娜  - 怎樣?
- Janet! - What?
- 我會處理  - 那就他媽的處理好  蘭迪
- I will handle this. - Then fucking handle it, Randy.
克裡夫...
Cliff...
衣服脫下  收拾東西
get the wardrobe off, get your shit,
有多遠滾多遠
and get off the lot.
也是公平啦
Fair enough.
# Because I'm hungry for those good things, baby #
# Hungry through and through #
# I'm hungry for that sweet life, baby #
# With a real fine girl like you #
噢  怎麼啦?
Aw. What's the matter?
你怕我會跟吉姆·莫里森說
Are you afraid I'll tell Jim Morrison
你聽著保羅·瑞佛和奇襲者樂團的歌跳舞?
you were dancing to Paul Revere and the Raiders?
他們對你來說不夠酷嗎?
Are they not cool enough for you?
# Custom-tailored world #
# That I wanna own someday #
# With a special place up high #
那個邋遢的渾球是誰?
Who's this shaggy asshole?
你好  有什麼事嗎?
Hello? Can I help you?
噢  你好  我來找泰瑞
Oh, yeah. Hey, man. I'm looking for Terry.
我是泰瑞和鄧尼斯·威爾森的朋友
I'm a friend of Terry's and Dennis Wilson's.
泰瑞和甘蒂不住這裡了  這裡現在是波蘭斯基的住宅
Well, Terry and Candy don't live here anymore. This is the Polanski residence now.
真的嗎?  他搬走了?
Really? He moved?
靠
Dang.
你知道他搬去哪了嗎?
Uh, you know...? You know where?
我不清楚  但房東保羅也許知道
I'm not sure, but the owner of the property, Paul, might.
他在客房裡
He's in the guest house.
是誰啊  傑?
Who is it, Jay?
沒事  親愛的  是泰瑞的朋友
It's okay, honey. It's a friend of Terry's.
- 往後面走  - 衷心感謝
- Yeah, just take the back path. - Thank you kindly.
再會
Ma'am.
一小時內回來
All right, that's an hour!
瑞克  我知道他們剛午休放飯
Hey, Rick. I know they just broke for lunch,
但你得等至少一個小時才能吃東西
but you need to wait at least an hour before you can eat.
讓鬍子上的膠水有時間幹
Give that glue a chance to dry.
別擔心  親愛的  我可以看書
Oh, no worries, honey. I got my book.
請問  惡棍酒吧在哪裡?
Say, say, where's the bad-guy saloon?
直走  穿過西部城
You just go straight through the Western town,
右轉再左轉就會看到了
take a right and a left, and you see it right there.
謝了  親愛的
Thanks, honey.
Can we move to number two?
How is his bounce?
Can I get a bounce there?
Just grab the crescent wrench, come right back.
Just make it a quick one.
- Tim! - Looks great. Right there.
你好
Hello.
呃...
Would...
如果我也坐你旁邊看書  會不會打擾到你?
Would it bother you if I sat next to you and read my book too?
我不知道
I don't know.
你會打擾我嗎?
Would you bother me?
我會試著不打擾?
I'll try not to.
坐吧
Sit.
唉
Ah.
抱歉  不好意思
Sorry. Sorry about that. Ahem.
你不吃午餐?
You don't eat lunch?
我午餐後有一場戲
I've got a scene after lunch.
是嗎?
Yeah?
上戲前吃午餐會讓我變得遲鈍
Eating lunch before I do a scene makes me sluggish.
我相信"演員"的工作...
I believe it's the job of an actor...
我說的詞是"演員"  而不是"女演員"
And I say "actor," not "actress,"
因為加上性別沒有意義
because the word "actress" is nonsensical.
演員的工作  要避免任何會影響演出的障礙
It's the actor's job to avoid impediments to their performance.
演員的工作  要努力達成百分之百的效率
It's the actor's job to strive for 100 percent effectiveness.
儘管是不可能百分百  但是要有追求...
Naturally, we never succeed, but it's the pursuit...
才有意義
that's meaningful.
- 你是誰?  - 你可以叫我瑪拉貝拉
- Who are you? - You can call me Marabella.
你有姓氏嗎?
Mar... Marabella what?
瑪拉貝拉·蘭瑟
Marabella Lancer.
不  少來了  你的真名是什麼?
No, no, come on, come on. What's your real name?
在拍片時  我寧願用角色的名字稱呼
When we're on set, I'd prefer to only be referred to by my character's name.
有助於我投入故事的現實裡
It helps me invest in the reality of the story.
我試過兩種方法  身處角色時我總是比較出色
I've tried it both ways, and I'm always just a tiny bit better when I don't break character.
如果我可以更出色...
And if I can be a tiny bit better,
我就要更出色
I want to be.
你演那個惡棍  凱勒·迪卡杜
You're the bad guy. Caleb DeCoteau.
我以為是念"達可塔"
I thought it was pronounced Caleb "Dakota."
我挺確定是"迪卡杜"
I'm pretty sure it's "DeCoteau."
- 迪卡杜  - 嗯
- DeCoteau. - Mm.
迪卡杜  迪卡杜
DeCoteau. DeCoteau.
哼
Hmm.
你在讀什麼?
What are you reading?
華特·迪士尼的自傳
It's a biography on Walt Disney.
很有趣
It's fascinating.
他是天才  你知道嗎?
He's a genius, you know.
每半世紀或一百年才會有的那種天才
I mean, a once-in-every-50-or-100-years kind of genius.
你多大  十二歲嗎?
What are you, 12?
我八歲
I'm 8.
你在讀什麼?
What are you reading?
就一本西部小說
Just a Western.
什麼意思?  好看嗎?
What does that mean? Is it good?
- 挺不錯的  - 是什麼故事?
- Pretty good. - What's the story?
我還沒看完
I haven't finished it yet.
我沒要你講完整的故事
I didn't ask for the whole story.
是什麼概念的故事?
What's the idea of the story?
這個嘛
Well... ahem,
是關於一個偷牛的傢伙
it's about this guy who's a bronco buster.
是他一生的故事
It's the story of his life.
那人叫作"湯姆·布裡奇"
Guy's name is Tom Breezy,
但大家總是叫他"不稀奇"
but everyone always calls him Easy Breezy.
不稀奇二十幾歲的時候
Now, when Easy Breezy was in his 20s
他年輕帥氣  充滿活力
and-and-and young and good-looking, he could...
他能駕馭任何一匹馬
He could break any horse that you could throw at him.
過去他總是隨心所欲
Back then, he just had a way.
現在他步入不惑之年
Now he's into his, uh, late 30s
慘摔一跤  搞壞了髖關節
and he takes a bad fall, and it messes up his hip.
他並不是殘廢了
He's not... He's not... He's not crippled
或是其他什麼的
or anything like that, but...
但脊椎的問題前所未有的嚴重
But he's got spine problems he never had before, and he spends, uh...
每天多在痛苦中度過
more of his days in pain than he ever did before.
聽起來是本好小說
Jeepers, this sounds like a good novel.
是啊  還不錯
Yeah, it's not bad.
你讀到哪裡了?
Where are you in it?
大概一半
Mm. About midway.
不稀奇現在怎麼樣了?
What's happening to Easy Breezy now?
這個嘛  他...
Uh, he's, um... He...
他不是頂尖高手了
He's not the best anymore.
事實上  差遠了
In fact, far from it. And...
他開始承認自己變得...
he's coming to terms with what it's like to be slightly more...
越來越沒用...
use...
一天比一天更廢物
Slightly more useless each day.
沒關係  凱勒  沒關係的
I-it's okay, Caleb. It's okay.
聽起來是很悲傷的書
It sounds like a really sad book.
不稀奇真可憐
Poor Easy Breezy.
我根本還沒看就哭了
I'm practically crying, and I haven't even read it.
大概再過15年就該輪到你了
About 15 years, you'll be living it.
什麼?
What?
沒事  小可愛
Nothing, pumpkin puss. I'm just...
只是在逗你
I'm just teasing you.
你知道嗎?
You know something? You...
也許你說對了
You might be right about this book.
這本書給我的打擊比我想像的大
I think it hits harder than I gave it credit for.
我不喜歡"小可愛"這種名字
I don't like names like "pumpkin puss,"
但因為你心情不好
but since you're upset,
我們改天這談這個話題
we'll talk about that some other time.
# Yesterday a child came out to wonder #
# Caught a dragonfly inside a jar #
# Fearful when the sky was full of thunder #
# And tearful at the falling of a star #
# Then the child moved ten times round the seasons #
# Skated over ten clear frozen streams #
# Words like, when you're older, must appease him #
我只會到西木村
I'm only going as far as Westwood Village.
我有車搭就很感激了
Hey, beggars can't be choosers.
- 進來  - 謝謝
- Come on in. - Thanks.
# And the seasons they go round and round #
# And the painted ponies go up and down #
# We're captive on the carousel of time #
( 她是頂級少女 )
( 《瓊安娜》 )
- 太感謝了  - 我很樂意
- Thank you so much. - My pleasure.
- 祝你好運  - 謝謝
- Good luck on your adventure. - Thank you.
- 在大索爾玩得開心  - 謝謝你
- Have a good time in Big Sur. - Thank you so much.
- 保重  - 你也是
- Take care. - You too.
( 20世紀福斯 )
( M限制級電影正在放映 )
( 《紅杏出牆案外案》 )
( 主演: 喬治·佩帕德  珍·茜寶  查理斯·麥格勞 )
( 正在放映《勇破迷魂陣》 )
( 主演: 迪恩·馬丁  艾爾克·薩默  莎朗·塔特  關南施 )
( 迪恩·馬丁扮演"超級情報員麥漢" )
( 《勇破迷魂陣》 )
- 噢  嘿  - 你好
- Oh, hey. - Hello.
可以為你效勞嗎  女士?
How can I help you, young lady?
噢
Oh.
我來取我訂購得初版書  湯姆斯·哈代寫的〈苔絲〉
I'm here to pick up a first edition of Thomas Hardy's Tess of the d'Urbervilles I ordered.
用波蘭斯基的名字訂的
It's under Polanski.
你很懂書嘛  孩子
Yeah, you're talking books there, kid.
是啊  那本書很棒吧?
Oh, I know. Isn't it wonderful?
- 是的  - 我剛讀完
- Yeah. Oh, man. - I just read it.
- 我要買來送我老公  - 嗯
( 羅曼·波蘭斯基後來真的拍攝了電影版〈苔絲〉 )
- I'm getting it as a gift for my husband. - Mm.
- 瑞克·達爾頓?  - 正是
- Rick Dalton? - You bet.
吉姆·史塔奇  這是我的戲  歡迎加入
Jim Stacy. This is my show. Welcome aboard.
我們真得很高興有你這樣的專業演員  來演試播劇的反派
We're real glad to have a pro like you playing the heavy on the pilot.
而且我得說  我差點就拿到《麥克拉斯基的14拳》的角色
And I gotta tell you, I came damn close to being in The Fourteen Fists of McCluskey.
- 真的假的  - 真的
- No kidding. - Yeah.
我告訴你
Let me tell you, I...
我完全是因為運氣才得到角色
I just got my part-part by sheer luck.
開拍前兩周  還是由法比安演
Up until two weeks before shooting, Fabian was in the part.
但他拍《維吉尼亞人》時肩膀受傷  所以我才能演
Then-then he breaks his shoulder doing a Virginian. That's how I got it, so...
啊
Ah.
嘿  瑞克  我得問問我聽說的事情
Hey, Rick, I gotta ask you something I heard about.
你真得差點就能演《大逃亡》中史蒂夫·麥奎因的角色嗎?
Was it true you almost got the McQueen part in The Great Escape?
- 希特  是吧?  - 是希特上尉
- Hilts, isn't it? - Captain Hilts, actually.
- 嘗試逃脫17次  - 18次
- Seventeen escape attempts. - Eighteen.
從沒試鏡過  從沒開會過  從沒見過導演約翰·斯特奇斯
Never had an audition. Never had a meeting. Never met John Sturges.
所以  我想你不能說我差點得到那個角色
So, no, I don't think you could say I... I almost got the part, but...
- 工兵  工程師  - 飛行員
- Tunnel man, engineer. - Flier.
我想那是美國軍隊裡所稱的自命不凡的機師
I suppose what's called in the American Army, a hotshot pilot.
但我聽說  曾經有一度
But the story goes, for a brief moment,
麥奎因差點推掉這部片  而就在那一瞬間
McQueen almost passed on the movie, and during that brief moment,
顯然  我在一個四人名單裡
I, apparently, was on a list of four.
你有別的打算?
You have other plans?
我還沒到過柏林
I haven't seen Berlin yet from the ground or from the air,
戰爭結束前  我打算飛去一趟
and I plan on doing both before the war's over.
你和誰?
You and who?
- 我和另外三個叫喬治的  - 哪三個?
- Me and... Me and three Georges. - Which three Georges?
派伯  馬哈裡斯  和查格裡斯
Peppard, Maharis and Chakiris.
- 真是的  - 對呀
- Oh, man. - Yeah.
你一定很受傷
That's gotta hurt.
是啊  我沒得演
Yeah, well, I didn't get it,
麥奎因演了
McQueen did it,
而且坦白說  我本來就沒機會
and, frankly, I never had a chance.
關禁閉十天  希特
Ten days isolation, Hilts.
希特上尉
Captain Hilts.
20天
Twenty days.
隨便
Right.
對了  我出來的時候你還在嗎?
Oh, you'll still be here when I get out?
關進冷藏室
Cooler.
( 《勇破迷魂陣》 )
( 正在放映《勇破迷魂陣》 )
( 領銜主演: 迪恩·馬丁 )
( 迪恩·馬丁第四次扮演"超級情報員麥漢" )
( 聯合主演: 艾爾克·薩默  莎朗·塔特  關南施 )
( 奈傑爾·格林  蒂娜·露易絲 )
- 請給我一張票  - 75分
- One, please. - Seventy-five cents.
如果我在電影裡是多少錢?
What if I'm in the movie?
什麼意思?
What do you mean?
我是說  我出演了這部電影
I mean, I'm in the movie.
我是莎朗·塔特
I'm Sharon Tate.
- 你演了這部片?  - 嗯哼
- You're in this? - Mm-hm.
我演卡爾森小姐  那個傻妞
I play Miss Carlson, the klutz.
那個就是我
That's me.
但那是《娃娃谷》裡面的女生
But that's the girl from Valley of the Dolls.
那就是我啊  《娃娃谷》裡面的女生
Well, that's me, the girl from Valley of the Dolls.
真的嗎?
Really?
真的
Really.
喂  魯賓  出來
Hey, Rubin! Come out here.
這位是《娃娃谷》裡面的女生
This is the girl from Valley of the Dolls.
- 帕蒂·杜克?  - 不是  是另一個
- Patty Duke? - No, the other one.
- 《冷暖人間》裡面的女生?  - 不是  是另一個
- The girl from Peyton Place? - No, the other one.
後來跑去演成人電影那個
The one who ends up doing dirty movies.
- 噢  - 她出演了這部片
- Oh. - She's in this movie.
- 噢  - 莎朗·塔特
- Oh. - Sharon Tate.
歡迎你來棕熊戲院  塔特小姐
Well, welcome to the Bruin, Miss Tate.
謝謝你光臨本戲院
Thank you for coming to our theater.
- 你要進來看電影嗎?  - 可以嗎?
- Would you like to come in and see the show? - Could I?
那當然
By all means.
謝謝
Thank you.
嘿  我可以拍照嗎?
Hey, can I get a picture?
- 噢  當然  - 好
- Oh, sure.  - Okay.
你站海報旁邊好了  這樣大家就會知道你是誰
You know, why don't you stand over by the poster so people will know who you are.
好啊  麻煩你拿一下
Okay. Could you?
( 《無情職業快槍手》 )
想吃點什麼嗎?
Would you like some refreshments?
- 不用了  謝謝  - 觀影愉快
- Oh, I'm fine. Thank you. - Enjoy the show.
# Well now see #
# C. C. Rider #
# I said see, see #
# What you have done now #
# You made me love you #
# Na na na, now, your man has come #
( 《狂野機車手》即將上映 )
# Alright #
- 我能問你一個問題嗎?  - 我希望你能
- Can I ask you a personal question? - I wish you would.
你這樣的好男生怎麼會被牽連進暴力社團呢?
How did a nice boy like you get involved with a group like the Heads?
當我被美國革命的女兒們拒絕後  便重返了他們的陣營
I turned to them after I was rejected by the Daughters of the American Revolution.
# I can't turn you loose #
# If I do, I'm gonna lose my mind, ba-baby #
# Do it baby, why don't ya? #
# Why don't you gimme everything I want #
# And it's for me alone #
很舒適的飯店
Very pleasant hotel here.
- 麥漢先生  - 什麼事?
- Mr. Helm? - Yes?
噢
Oh!
我是佛莉雅
I'm Freya.
歡迎來到丹麥  麥漢先生
Welcome to Denmark, Mr. Helm.
這些是給你的  街道地圖  景點
These are for you. Street maps, places of interest.
這也是給你的
This is for you too.
- 是哪一年份的?  - 1949年
- What year was that? - 1949.
噢  很好的年份
Oh, that's a very good year.
- 我會盡力協助你  - 你真好
- I'm here to help any way I can. - Very nice of you.
有什麼需要我做的嗎?
Is there anything you'd like me to do?
- 有的  女士  有一兩件事  - 是的  先生
- Yes, Ma'am, a couple things. - Yes, sir.
麻煩你離開我的相主機殼  好嗎?
Would you mind getting off my camera case, please?
- 噢  對不起  - 噢  沒關係的
- Oh, I'm sorry. - Oh, that's all right.
- 很抱歉  - 沒關係
- I'm so sorry. - That's okay.
抱歉...
I'm sorry about...
歡迎來到丹麥
Welcome to Denmark.
你這間飯店真不簡單
This is some kind of hotel you've got here.
半瓶酒總比一滴不剩來得好
Half a bottle is better than none.
早安  拍檔
Morning, partner.
以後再來見你
Probably come by to see you later.
打擾了  笨蛋
That's far enough, jughead.
我不是笨蛋
Name's not jughead.
你在這裡做什麼  小子?
What you doing around here, boy?
我口渴  這裡是酒吧  不是嗎?
I'm thirsty. That's a saloon, ain't it?
是啊  這是酒吧
Oh, yeah, that's a saloon.
- 只是你不能進來  - 吉伯特先生
- Only you can't come in. - Mr. Gilbert.
我不想打擾你賺錢
Don't let me stop you from earning your money.
我知道你賣完墨西哥粽時  會有多無聊多焦慮
I know how bored and restless you get when you run out of tamales.
但是  吉伯特先生  如果我是你
But, Mr. Gilbert, if I was you,
我會查出那笨蛋的名字
I'd find out that jughead's name.
容我介紹兩位
Allow me to introduce the two of you.
這位是鮑伯·吉伯特
This here is Bob Gilbert.
那個生意人?
The Businessman?
沒錯
That's right.
生意人鮑伯·吉伯特  他是哪位  凱勒?
Business Bob Gilbert. And who might he be, Caleb?
他嘛  那傢伙名叫馬德里
Well, that's a fella by the name of Madrid.
強尼·馬德里
Johnny Madrid.
強尼·馬德里是哪根蔥呀?
Who's Johnny Madrid?
他不是本地人
He ain't from round here.
不  說真的  他是誰  凱勒?
No, really. Who is he, Caleb?
你很快就會知道了...
Oh, you're about to find out...
生意人
Businessman.
我等著你呢  吉伯特
Ready when you are, Gilbert.
強尼·馬德里
Johnny Madrid.
多久沒見了?
How long has it been?
大概三年前在  華瑞斯之後就沒見過了
Since that time in Juárez, about three years ago.
進來喝一杯
Well, come on in and have a drink.
既然如此...
Hell, in that case...
我請你喝一杯吧  凱勒
buy you a drink, Caleb?
當然好  強尼
Sure, Johnny.
來杯梅茲卡爾如何?  像在華瑞斯那時一樣
How about some mezcal? Like that time in Juárez.
那天死了很多人
A lot of people died that day.
是啊
Yes, they did.
但我們打得很爽
But we had a good time.
不是嗎?
Didn't we?
是啊
Yeah, we did.
你先請  迪卡杜
After you, DeCoteau.
佩比  給我滾去顧吧台  我有客人
Pepe! Get your behind behind that bar. I have a guest.
豆子好吃嗎?
How's the beans?
我吃過更難吃的
I've had worse.
一塊錢
One dollar.
敬我的妻子和我所有的情人
To my wife and all my sweethearts.
願她們永遠不會碰面
May they never meet.
馬德里先生  願意來我這桌  陪我招待客人嗎?
Señor Madrid, you care to join me at my table where I entertain my guests?
我很樂意  迪卡杜先生
I'd be delighted, Monsieur DeCoteau.
酒瓶帶著
Take the bottle with you.
強尼啊
So, Johnny, ahem...
你來墨西哥做什麼?
what brings you to Arroyo del Oro?
噢  你懂我的  凱勒
Oh, you know me, Caleb.
為了錢
Money.
誰付你錢?
And who's paying around here?
我希望會是你
I hope you.
哼
Huh.
你聽說過我的什麼事?
And what have you heard about me?
我聽說過蘭瑟農場
I heard about the Lancer Ranch.
你養的那些牛
All the cattle you've appropriated.
很多土地  很多牛  很多錢  沒有法律
A lot of land, a lot of cows, a lot of money, no law to speak of,
除了一個老頭和一些墨西哥工人  什麼都沒有
and nothing but an old man and some Mexican ranch hands to shoo you off.
喂  你那位拉小提琴的辣妹女兒去哪了?
Say, where's that chili pepper daughter of yours with the fiddle?
她睡了
She's asleep.
叫醒她啊
Wake her the heck up, get her down here
讓她帶上琴和弓  下來娛樂我的客人
with her fiddle and her bow, and entertain my guest.
是  先生
Sí, señor.
但我求你  這次別傷害她  好嗎?
But, please, don't hurt her this time.
我不會傷害她  我只是要她拉琴
I ain't gonna hurt her. I just want her to play the fiddle.
下一句?  "快去找她"  然後咧?
Line? "Go... Go fetch her and tell her" what?
"快去找她  說我會賞她一大枚五元金幣"
"Go fetch her and tell her I'll give her a fat $5 gold piece..."
對  "快去找她  說我會賞她一大枚五元金幣"
Right. Go fetch her and tell her I'll give her a fat-fat $5 gold piece,
"她得用力死命地拉琴"  對吧?
she play her little chili pepper heart out, right?
- 對  - 知道了
- Right. - Got it.
我不會傷害她  我只是要她拉琴
I ain't gonna hurt her. I just want her to play the fiddle.
快去找她  說我會賞她一大枚五元金幣
Now, go fetch her and tell her I'll give her a fat $5 gold piece,
她得用力死命地拉琴
she play her little chili pepper heart out.
去啊
Go on.
強尼
So, Johnny,
你還聽說了什麼?
what else you heard?
哼
Hmm.
我聽說你把蘭瑟逼得很緊
I heard you're pushing Lancer pretty hard,
但是蘭瑟有錢
but Lancer's got money.
總有一天
At some point,
他會找幫手反擊
he's gonna hire some guns and push back.
- 提詞  提詞  - "也許他已經找了"
- Line. Line. Line, line, line. - "Maybe he already has."
也許他...
Maybe...
他媽的  我搞砸了  山姆
Goddamn it! I fucked this whole thing up, Sam.
繼續
Keep going!
- 我搞砸了  - 撐過去  瑞克
- I fucked this up. - Fight through it.
可以重來嗎?  拜託  可以暫停嗎?
Can we just go back? Please, can we just cut?
- 不  就他媽的繼續說你的臺詞  - 不  山姆  拜託
- No. Just say the fucking line! - No, really, Sam, please.
- "也許他已經找了"  - 好啦
- "Maybe he already has." - All right!
- "也許他已經找了"  - 好啦  媽的
- "Maybe he already has!" - All right, goddamn it!
好啦  好啦
All right, all right!
唔
Woo!
你是個該死的惡棍  瑞克  加油
You're a goddamn outlaw, Rick. Come on, now.
呼  唔
Hoo! Woo!
我可以  我可以
I got it. I got it.
往後退一點  可以嗎?
Go back a bit, would you?
不  他說得對  回上一段
No, he's right. Back to one.
- 運用你所有的情緒  - 我會的
- Okay, now, use all that, baby. - I'm gonna use it.
- 我行的  - 全情投入
- Oh, I'm gonna use it. - Put it all inside.
我行的
I'm gonna use it.
預備...
And...
開始
action.
我聽說你把蘭瑟逼得很緊
I heard you're pushing Lancer pretty hard,
但是蘭瑟有錢
but Lancer's got money.
總有一天
At some point,
他會找幫手反擊
he's gonna hire some guns and push back.
也許他已經找了
Maybe he already has.
也許吧
Maybe.
也許我不喜歡蘭瑟
Maybe I don't like Lancer.
也許我不喜歡他的靴子
Maybe I don't like his boots.
也許我不喜歡他用靴子踐踏別人的樣子
Maybe I don't like the way he uses those boots to step on people.
他媽的什麼情況?
What the fuck was that?!
老天呐
Jesus Christ!
操
Fuck!
一坨廢物
Piece of shit.
他媽的  瑞克  我對天發誓
Fucking damn it, Rick, I swear to God.
該死的忘詞
Forgot your fucking lines,
在所有人面前那樣丟臉
embarrassed yourself like that in front of all those goddamn people!
你整晚喝酒  該死的又開始酗酒
You were drinking all night, fucking drinking again,
八杯他媽的威士卡酸酒
eight goddamn fucking whiskey sours.
他媽的亂搞
Fucking bullshit.
你他媽沒用的酒鬼
You're a fucking miserable drunk.
他媽的記不住臺詞
Not fucking remembering your fucking lines.
我排練過  現在看起來像是我該死的沒排練
I practiced them, and now I don't look like I goddamn practiced them!
他媽的活像在耍猴戲
You're sitting there like a fucking baboon!
去他媽的八杯威士卡酸酒
Fuck! Eight fucking whiskey sours.
他媽的喝三四杯還不夠  還喝了八杯
I couldn't stop at fucking three or four. I have eight!
為什麼?  他媽的酒鬼
Why?! You're a fucking alcoholic.
他媽的喝太多了
You fucking drink too much, huh?
他媽的每天晚上喝
Every fucking night. Every fucking night.
完了  他媽的完蛋了
That's it, that's fucking it!
完了
That's fucking it.
馬上戒酒  好嗎?
You stop drinking right now, all right?
對自己發誓  他媽的會戒酒
Make a promise to yourself. You're gonna stop fucking drinking.
操
Oh, fuck it.
該死
Damn it!
做給那小屁孩看看  給該死的吉姆·史塔奇看看
You show that little fucking girl. You're gonna show that goddamn Jim Stacy.
要在那該死的片場讓大家見識到  瑞克·達爾頓是他媽的大人物
You're gonna show them on that goddamn fucking set who the fuck Rick Dalton is, all right?
我告訴你
Let me tell you something.
你臺詞說不好
You don't get these lines right,
我今晚就他媽打爆你的頭
I'm gonna blow your fucking brains out tonight.
懂嗎?  你的腦漿會噴在你的爛泳池裡
All right? Your brains are gonna be splattered all over your goddamn pool.
我是認真的  他媽的廢物
I mean it, motherfucker.
振作起來
Get your shit together.
- 我有進步嗎?  - 非常好
- Better? Okay. - It's great.
女士們先生們...
Ladies and gentlemen...
# 洛杉磯電臺 #
# KHJ Los Angeles #
下午3點31分  這是唐·斯蒂爾音樂秀
3:31 in Los Angeles. This is The Real Don Steele.
# I know that it's ten #
# And you're stayin' in #
# La la la la la la la la la #
# And you're stayin' home #
# And I'm all alone #
# La la la la la la la la la #
# Won't you won't you won't you bring a little water #
# Bring a little wine #
# Bring a little lovin' #
# I feel fine #
# Know that you want to #
# I know that you do #
# Come in here and love with me #
# Hot August night #
# And the leaves hanging down #
# And the grass on the ground #
# Smelling sweet #
# Move up the road #
# To the outside of town #
# And the sound of that good gospel beat #
嘿
Hey!
嗨
Hi.
嗯
Huh
.# Where there ain't no trees  Where there ain't no trees #
哇唔
Woo!
# And that gospel group  And that gospel group #
野姑娘
-Shit.
# Tellin' you and me  Tellin' you and me #
# It's Love, Brother Love, say #
# Brother Love's Travelling Salvation Show #
去你媽的  死條子
Fuck you, you fucking pig!
不會吧
Oh, no.
# And grab the old ladies #
# And everyone goes #
# 'Cause everyone knows #
# Brother Love's show #
你好啊  辣妹
Hello, hot stuff.
看來第三次就會有好運
Looks like third time's the charm.
醃黃瓜好吃嗎?
Mm. How were those pickles?
超贊  是高檔貨
Real good. They were the fancy kind.
- 嗯  - 嗯
- Mmm. - Mmm.
載我一程吧?
Give me a lift?
你要去哪?
Where are you going?
查茲窩斯
I'm going to Chatsworth.
查茲窩斯?
Chatsworth?
你整天在大馬路上攔車
You hitch up and down Burbank Boulevard all day
直到有人願意載你去查茲窩斯?
till someone says they'll drive you to Chatsworth?
遊客喜歡載我
Tourists love to drive me.
我是他們加州旅行最喜歡的部分
I'm their favorite part of their I.A. vacation.
他們讓好萊塢嬉皮女搭便車去片場
They'll be telling stories about the Hollywood hippie girl
這個故事可以說一輩子
that they gave a ride to the movie ranch for the rest of their lives.
等等  史潘片場?
Wait, Spahn Movie Ranch?
- 對啊  - 你要去史潘片場?
- Yeah. - That's where you're going? Spahn Movie Ranch?
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
- 你去那裡幹嘛?  - 我住那裡啊
- Why you going there? - I live there.
- 一個人住?  - 不  我和朋友住
- Alone? - No. Me and my friends.
所以你和一群跟你一樣的朋友  都住在史潘片場?
So you and a bunch of friends like you all live at Spahn Movie Ranch?
對啊
Yeah.
上來吧  我載你去
Well, hop in. I'll take you there.
太好了
Great!
# And when your heart is troubled #
# You gotta reach out your other hand #
# Reach it out to the man up there #
# 'Cause that's what he's there for #
你要從這裡上高速公路
Go down here and get on the Hollywood Freeway.
我知道路
I know where it is.
你是以前在那裡拍電影的老牛仔還是怎樣?
Are you some old cowboy guy that used to make movies there?
哇噢
Whoa!
什麼?
What?
我只是很驚訝  你對我的描述這麼精確
I'm just surprised how accurate that description of me really is.
在史潘片場拍過片的老牛仔
Some old cowboy guy that used to shoot movies at Spahn Ranch.
所以你過去曾在片場拍西部片?
So you used to make Westerns at the ranch back in the old-timey days?
如果你說的過去是指八年前的電視劇
Well, if by "the old-timey days," you mean television eight years ago,
沒錯
yeah.
你是演員嗎?
Are you an actor?
不  我是特技演員
No, I'm a stuntman.
特技演員
You're a stuntman.
那更好
That's way better.
為什麼更好?
Why is that way better?
- 演員很虛假  - 噢
- Actors are phony. - Oh.
他們只會念別人寫的臺詞
They just say lines that other people write
在愚蠢的電視劇裡假裝殺人
and pretend to murder people on their stupid TV shows.
但是在越南  每天都有人真的被殺
Meanwhile, real people are being murdered every day in Vietnam.
# Hey, little girl in the high school sweater #
# Gee, but I'd like to know you better #
# Just a-swingin' your books and chewin' gum #
# Lookin' just like a juicy plum #
# Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, little girl #
要我幫你吹喇叭嗎?
Want me to suck your cock while driving?
# Hey, little girl in the black silk stockings #
# Gee, but you got my heart rockin' #
- 你幾歲?  - 什麼?
- How old are you? - What?
你幾歲?
How old are you?
哇啊
Wow, man.
好久沒人問我這個問題了
That's the first time anybody asked that in a long time.
答案是?
What's the answer?
好  要玩猜一猜是吧?
Okay. We gonna play kiddie games?
18歲  比較放心了嗎?
Eighteen. Feel better?
你有像是駕照之類的證件嗎?
You got some ID, you know, like a driver's license or something?
- 你在搞笑嗎?  - 我沒有
- Are you joking? - No, I'm not.
我需要官方檔證明你18歲了
I need to see something official that verifies that you're 18,
但你沒有  因為你還沒滿18歲
which you don't have because you're not.
真掃興啊  老兄
Talk about a bring-down bummer, dude.
就是在說你
That's you.
是呀
Yeah.
顯然  我年紀雖小但能搞
Obviously, I'm not too young to fuck you.
但是  顯然你老到不肯搞
But obviously, you are too old to fuck me.
我老到不能因為和未成年性愛而去坐牢
What I'm too old to do is go to jail for poontang.
我這輩子一直在躲牢獄之災  還沒失敗過
Prison's been trying to get me all my life. It ain't got me yet.
真的要坐牢  也不會是因為你
The day it does, it won't be because of you.
別介意
No offense.
親愛的  你沒事吧?
You all right, honey?
她好得很  不是嗎  小妮子?
She's just fine, ain't you, shorty?
我沒事  史考特
I'm fine, Scott.
他們沒傷害你吧?
They haven't hurt you?
攝影師準備好了  達爾頓先生
Camera's ready, Mr. Dalton.
我馬上出去
I'll be right out.
戰爭
The war.
我在印度隨著英國騎兵出征...
I rode with the British cavalry in Indi...
注意了  五秒後開機
Stand by, guys. We're going in five.
蘭瑟的手下來了
Lancer's boys are here!
那老惡霸來了嗎?
The old man here?
沒來  但他兒子來了
Nada. But the son is.
啊  嘿嘿
Ah. Heh, heh.
來自波士頓的那個
The one from Boston.
我不知道  你從波士頓來的?
I don't know. You from Boston?
對
Yes.
是波士頓那個
It's the Boston one!
其它人待在外面  讓她哥哥進來
Keep the others outside. Let the brother come in.
你聽到了  波士頓小子
You heard him, Boston.
進來吧  波士頓小子
Come on in, Boston.
你看  親愛的?
See, honey?
我說過他們會來
I told you they'd come to parlay.
你沒事吧  親愛的?
You all right, honey?
噢  她好得很
Oh, she's just fine.
不是嗎  小妮子?
Ain't you, shorty?
我沒事  史考特
I'm fine, Scott.
他們沒傷害你吧?
They haven't hurt you?
我還沒動手呢
Not yet, I ain't.
但在一瞬間...
But that can all change...
就可能改變
like that.
我說...
Say...
你是怎麼瘸腿的?
where'd you get that limp?
- 因為戰爭  - 嗯
- From the war. - Mm.
哪一邊?
Which side?
我在印度隨英國騎兵出征
I rode with the British cavalry in India.
嗯
Mm.
你那是什麼造型?
What'd they call that outfit?
賓高槍騎兵
Bengal Lancers.
真好笑
Now, now, now, that is funny.
- 真好笑  - 沒那麼好笑
- That is funny. - That's not so funny.
你不懂嗎?  賓高  我還賓果咧
Don't you get it? "Bengal Lancer"?
啥?
Hm?
噢
Oh, yeah.
我聽懂了
I get it now.
- 是有點好笑  - 正是
- That is kind of funny. - It is.
你知道綁架是要處吊刑的
You do know kidnapping is a hanging offense.
打爆小女孩的頭也是
So is blowing the heads off little girls.
但他們只能吊死我一次  對吧?
But they can only hang me once, right?
所以...
So...
你來是為了閒聊?
you come down here for a... For a Boston social?
- 還是我們要談個價錢?  - 多少?
- Or we gonna talk price? - How much?
我想要五萬美元
I'd say $50,000 would buy me
那可以令我在墨西哥買到好多咖哩雞
a whole lot of chicken mole in Mexico.
那可是一大筆錢
That's a lot of money.
她可是一大美女
Well, she's a lot of little girl.
你不同意嗎?
Or don't you agree?
我同意
I agree.
接下來呢?
So, what's next?
我會派人去你的農場
Well, I'll send one of my boys out to your ranch
然後告訴你細節  但是...
to fill you in on all the details, but, uh...
有件事我現在就可以告訴你
the one detail I'm gonna fill you in on right now is this:
我不要什麼阿貓阿狗的帶錢來
I don't want no beaner bronco buster handing me that $50,000.
我要那老頭親自送來
I want the old man himself.
莫道·蘭瑟放五萬塊在我手上...
Murdoch Lancer puts $50,000 in my lap...
否則我就把這小鬼丟到井裡
or I heave this little pitcher down a well!
懂嗎  波士頓小子?
You got that, Boston?
懂嗎?
Huh?
懂
Yeah.
好了  傳話的
All right, messenger boy.
把我的訊息送回去
Deliver my message.
想像自己是邪惡且性感的哈姆雷特
Give me evil, sexy Hamlet.
沉浸其中  享受一下
Settle into it. Enjoy it.
卡
And cut!
天啊
Oh, boy.
我沒傷到你吧  瑪拉貝拉?
I didn't hurt you there, Marabella, with that throw, did I?
不  我沒事  我有護墊
No, no, no. I'm good. I got pads on.
我總是把自己摔在地上  好玩而已
And I throw myself on the floor just for fun,
即使沒人付錢要我這麼做
even when I'm not getting paid.
大門弄好
The gate's clean.
瑞克  瑞克
Rick, Rick, Rick.
握個手
Put her there.
- 就是這樣  - 真的嗎?
- That was it. - Really?
棒極了
That was absolutely fantastic.
- 謝謝  - 我超愛
- Oh, thank you. - I loved it.
把小女孩拽到地上  效果超好
Your idea about throwing the little girl on the ground just worked like a charm.
我想你提到莎士比亞
I figured you said Shakespeare, so... Yeah.
沒錯  就是我說"嚇我"的意思
That's right. That was... That's what I mean by "scare me."
- 對  -  邪惡的哈姆雷特讓人害怕
- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. - Evil Hamlet scares people.
- 好的  - 噢  對了
- All right. - Oh, and by the way...
"阿貓阿狗"?  這句話從哪裡來的?
"Beaner bronco buster"? Where the hell did that come from?
- 即興演出  - 好極了
- I don't know. Improv. - That was wonderful.
超到位的即興演出
It was just... That was a triple alliterative improv.
平常看不到的
You don't hear those too often.
- 好了  我們沒問題了  - 好的
- Okay? We're good. - All right.
- 不用再來一次?  - 不用  拍完了
- We don't... Don't need to go again? - We're done.
- 太棒了  - 好的
- That was fantastic. - All right.
好了  繼續拍下一場妓院的戲
Okay, moving on. We're in the bordello.
準備下場戲
Next setup!
那是我這輩子看過最好的演技
That was the best acting I've ever seen in my whole life.
謝謝你
Thank you. Heh.
瑞克·達爾頓最他媽厲害
Rick fucking Dalton.
有車
That's a car.
沒聽過這輛車
That's a strange car.
小蛇  去看看誰在外頭
Snake, go see who's outside.
所以是誰?
So who is it?
我還不確定
I ain't for sure yet.
是輛酷炫的黃色凱迪拉克
It's a bitchen yellow Coupe de Ville.
盯著他們
Keep an eye on him.
來啊
Come on.
人都死哪去了?
Where the hell is everybody?
嘿  吉普賽呢?
Hey, where's Gypsy?
她在修車廠
She's down by the chop shop.
- 嘿  - 哈囉
- Hey! - Hello!
吉普賽  我要介紹我的新朋友給你
Gypsy! I want you to come meet my new friend.
一個穿夏威夷衫的大叔載咪咪貓回來了
Some old-looking dude in a Hawaiian shirt who just gave Pussycat a ride home.
他只是載她回來?
He just gave her a lift?
沒  她帶他來片場跟大家認識
Nope. She's bringing him down the ranch to meet everybody.
守在門邊  他過來的話跟我說
Stay by the door. Tell me if he starts coming this way.
- 歡迎來我們的社區  - 謝謝邀請
- Welcome to our community. - Thanks for having me.
謝謝你載我們的寶貝咪咪回家
Thank you for giving our precious Pussy a ride home.
別客氣
Think nothing of it.
我們愛咪咪
We love Pussy.
我也是啊
Yes, we do.
大家都去哪了?  孩子們呢?
Hey, where is everybody? Where's the children?
大家都去聖塔芭芭拉了
Everybody left for Santa Barbara.
真的嗎?
Really?
查理走了?  大家都走了?
Charlie's gone? Everybody left?
也不是大家啦  但是大部分都走了
Well, not "everybody" everybody, but mostly everybody.
討厭
Drag.
我真的想讓克裡夫認識查理
I really wanted Cliff to meet Charlie.
我覺得查理會很喜歡你
I think Charlie's really gonna dig you.
- 天使  等等  - 那就下次吧
- Angel, hold up. - Well, maybe next time.
對啊  你一定要回來
Yeah, you got to come back.
- 好嗎?  - 好啊  當然
- Yeah? - Yeah, sure.
跟你風光的當年比起來怎麼樣?
So how's it all comparing to your glory days?
變了不少
Well, things have changed.
上馬動作不錯噢  康妮
Not a bad mount, Connie.
我以前在田納西州天天騎馬
I used to ride horses every day back in Tennessee.
- 是嗎?  - 每天?
- Is that right? - Every day?
好啦  是每星期
Well, every week.
好了
All right.
他很可愛吧?
Ain't she just darling?
好  我叫露露
So, uh, my name is Lulu.
這位是泰斯
This is Tex.
我們會帶你們走上小徑
We're gonna be leading you on a great trail ride
穿過美麗的聖蘇珊娜峽谷
through the beautiful Santa Susana canyons.
- 寇特  我聽說你騎馬已經很有經驗了  - 是的
- Now, Curt, I hear you're already an experienced rider. - Yes.
- 你也是嗎  康妮?  - 我也是
- Yeah, so are you, Connie? - Yes, I am.
嘿  泰斯  過來
Hey, Tex? Come here.
既然你們都騎過馬
So, uh, if you're both experienced riders,
我想我們就開心騎囉
I guess we'll just make this ride about having fun.
準備好來點樂趣了嗎?
You ready to have some fun?
咪咪帶了個男人回來
So Pussycat brought back some guy with her.
吉普賽要你去看看
Gypsy wants you to go give him a look-see.
好  當然
Yeah. Sure thing.
噢  這位元你一定要認識
Oh, and here's someone you absolutely have to meet.
我們最喜歡的孩子之一
One of our most favorite sons.
泰斯  過來跟克裡夫打招呼
Tex, come on over here and say hi to Cliff.
你好  克裡夫
Howdy, Cliff.
泰斯  你是從德州哪裡來的?
Tex. What part of Texas you from?
你沒聽過的地方  柯普鎮
Oh, a place you never heard of. Copeville.
你去過休士頓嗎?
Ah. Ever been to Houston?
當然去過
Course I have.
我曾在休士頓的勞改營待過兩周
Yeah, I spent two weeks once on a Houston chain gang.
八月的時候  苦日子
In August, no less.
聽起來不太好玩
That doesn't sound like a whole lot of fun.
我只能說  那是我最後一次打斷條子的下巴
It's the last cop's jaw I ever broke, I can tell you that.
哇
Man...
查理會超愛你
Charlie's gonna dig you.
這夏威夷佬似乎不賴
The Hawaiian guy seems to be okay.
大家說話氣氛很友善
Everybody's talking all friendly.
- 好好享受  - 謝謝
- Enjoy your day! - Thank you.
泰斯打量過他  現在要走了
Tex checked him out, and now he's riding away.
如果他過來  讓我知道
If he comes this way, let me know.
嘿  喬治·史潘還擁有這個片場嗎?
Hey, does George Spahn still own this ranch?
是啊  還是喬治的
Yeah, George still owns it.
- 他還住在這裡?  - 是啊
- Does he still live here? - Yeah.
他還是住在那裡嗎?
Does he still live right there?
是啊
Yeah.
他在嗎?
Is he here now?
應該在吧
I guess so.
喬治允許你們待在這裡?
So George gave you all permission to be here?
當然啊
Course he did.
你們全都在照顧他嗎?
And y'all take care of him?
噢  我們會照顧喬治
Oh, we take care of George.
我們愛喬治
We love George.
我跟老朋友打聲招呼沒問題吧?
Well, is there anything wrong with me saying hello to an old friend?
你不能現在見他
You can't see him right now.
為什麼不能現在見他?
Why can't I see him right now?
因為他在午睡
Because he's napping.
現在是他的午睡時間
This is his nap time.
我想要自己去瞧個究竟
Well, I think I'll just go see for myself.
搞不好他剛起床
You never know. He might have just woke up.
那夏威夷佬過來了
The old Hawaiian guy's coming this way.
好了  你們都滾吧  我來對付他
Okay, y'all, beat it. I'll handle this guy.
- # Every day, it's just fake it #  - 好吧
- # Every day, it's just fake it # - Fine.
# Let me show you a new place #
# Add it to your collection #
# Shine on down for this baby of mine #
# Mr. Moon, come on through #
# When Mr. Sun goes we'll be counting on you #
# Mr. Sun, make it fine #
# Shine on down for this baby of mine #
# Mr. Moon, come on through #
你是媽媽桑嗎?
You the mama bear?
- 有事嗎?  - 有
- Can I help you? - I hope so.
我是喬治的老朋友  想來打個招呼
I'm an old friend of George's. Thought I'd stop and say hello.
你人真好  但可惜你挑錯時間了
That's very nice of you, but you picked the wrong time.
喬治現在在午睡
George is taking a nap right now.
噢  真可惜
Oh, that is unfortunate.
是很可惜
Yes, it is.
- 你叫什麼名字?  - 克裡夫·布茲
- What's your name? - Cliff Booth.
你怎麼認識喬治的?
How do you know George?
我曾在這裡拍西部片
I used to shoot Westerns here at the ranch.
你最後一次見喬治是何時?
When was the last time you saw George?
噢  我想大概是...
Oh, I'd say about...
八年前
eight years ago.
噢  抱歉
Oh. I'm sorry.
我不知道你們倆這麼親近
I didn't realize the two of you were so close.
他醒來時  我會讓他知道你來過
When he wakes up, I'll let him know you came by.
我真得很想打聲招呼  我人都來了
I'd really like to say a quick hello now while I'm here.
大老遠跑來  不知道什麼時候會再經過
Came a long ways. Don't know when I'll get back this way again.
我明白  但恐怕不可能
Oh, I understand, but I'm afraid that's impossible.
不可能?  為什麼不可能?
Impossible? Why is that impossible?
因為我和喬治喜歡在周日夜看《聯邦調查局》和《牧野風雲》
Me and George like to watch TV on Sunday night, F.B.I. and Bonanza.
但喬治在晚上很容易睡著
but George finds it hard to keep awake,
所以我讓他現在睡午覺  才不會毀了我和喬治的電視時光
so I make him nap so I don't get gypped out of my TV time.
噢
Ah.
聽著  紅發女  我要進去了
Well, look, Red, I'm coming in there.
用我的兩隻眼睛  好好看看喬治
With my own two eyes, I'm gonna get a good look at George.
你這樣...
And this...
也擋不住我
ain't stopping me.
好吧
Okay.
隨你便
Suit yourself.
你從不知道
You never know.
你遇見的下個男生也許就是真愛
The next boy you meet may be the one.
如此乾淨  對你的皮膚十分有益
So clean, it's actually good for your skin.
新鮮且天然
So fresh and natural looking,
令你時刻為下次約會做好準備
you're always ready for next time.
你從不知道
And you never know,
你遇見的下個男生也許就是真愛
the next boy you meet may be the one.
閃光時刻
Sparkling drop of Retsyn.
他在後面?
He back there?
走到底最後一扇門
Door at the end of the hallway.
你可能得搖醒他  我早上搞得他不醒人事
You might have to shake him awake. I fucked his brains out this morning.
他可能累了
He may be tired.
對了  八年前先生
Oh, Mr. Eight Years Ago?
喬治瞎了  所以你可能得告訴他你是誰
George is blind, so you'll probably have to tell him who you are.
喬治  你醒著嗎?
George, you awake?
喬治?
George?
- 喬治  - 天呐
- George! - Jesus.
- 嗨  喬治  - 等一下
- Hi, George. - Wait a minute.
- 出什麼事了?  - 沒事
- What's going on? - Everything's all right.
- 抱歉打擾你  - 呃...
- I'm sorry to disturb you. - Uh...
- 你是誰?  - 克裡夫·布茲
- Who are you? - It's Cliff Booth.
我只是路過打聲招呼  看你過得如何
Just stopped in to say hello and see how you're doing.
約翰·威克斯·布恩?
John Wilkes Booth?
克裡夫·布茲
No, Cliff Booth.
誰啊?
Who's that?
我在這裡拍過《賞金律法》
I used to shoot Bounty Law here, George.
我是瑞克·達爾頓的特技替身
I was Rick Dalton's stunt double.
- 誰?  - 瑞克·達爾頓
- Who? - Rick Dalton.
達爾頓兄弟?
The Dalton Brothers?
不  是瑞克·達爾頓
No, Rick Dalton.
那是誰?
Who's that?
他是《賞金律法》的主角
He was the star of Bounty Law.
那你又是誰?
And who are you?
我是瑞克的特技替身
I was Rick's stunt double.
瑞克是誰?
Rick who?
不重要了  喬治
It don't matter, George.
我們以前是同事  我只是要確認你過得好
We were colleagues from the past, and I just wanted to make sure you're doing okay.
- 我過得不好  - 怎麼回事?
- I'm not doing okay. - What's the matter?
什麼鬼都看不到
Can't see shit.
就這麼回事
Would you call that "the matter"?
看不見  可以嗎?
The man can't see shit, okay?
很抱歉  我剛剛才聽人說的
I know. I'm sorry about that. I was told.
吱吱命令我午睡
Squeaky sent me to bed.
是外面那個紅發女嗎?
Would that be the little redhead out front?
你他媽怎麼回事?
What the fuck is the matter with you?
你把我叫醒
First you wake me up,
我不是才跟你說我他媽瞎了嗎
and now you're pretending that I didn't tell you I was fucking blind!
我怎麼會知道一直陪著我的那個女孩
How am I gonna know what the hell color the head
頭髮是什麼鬼顏色?
of the girl is that's with me all the time?
說得也是  喬治
Oh, fair enough, George.
- 免啦  老天  - 好吧
- No. Jesus Christ. - Come on, George. All right.
不是每個人都需要特技替身
Everyone don't need a stuntman.
我不知道你是誰
I don't know who you are...
但你今天感動了我
but you touched me today.
你來看我
You came to visit me.
現在我得回去睡了
Now I got to go back to sleep.
今晚要看《聯邦調查局》
I got to watch F.B.I. tonight.
我和吱吱一起看
I watch it with Squeaky.
我睡著的話  她會超不爽
She gets all pissed off if I fall asleep.
她超不爽的時候會怎樣  喬治?
What happens when she gets pissed off, George?
不會怎樣
Nothing.
我只是不想讓她失望
I just don't like to disappoint her.
所以你允許這些嬉皮來這裡?
So you gave all these hippies permission to be here?
你他媽哪位啊?
Just who the fuck are you?
克裡夫·布茲  我是特技演員
I'm Cliff Booth. I'm a stuntman.
我們曾經是同事  喬治
We used to work together, George.
我只是要確認你過得好
And I just want to make sure you're okay.
希望這群嬉皮沒有占你便宜
And that all these hippies aren't taking advantage of you.
- 吱吱嗎?  - 對
- Squeaky? - Yeah.
她愛我
She loves me.
所以你去吃屎吧
So suck on that.
你保重  喬治
You take care, George.
真該死
Goddamn it.
你讓我很丟臉
You embarrassed me.
是噢  抱歉了
Yeah, sorry about that.
你跟喬治談心談得如何?  覺得我們綁架他嗎?
How'd your little talk with George go? Are we kidnapping him?
我不會用這個詞
Not the word I'd use.
既然你跟他聊過了  你放心了嗎?
Now you've talked to him, you believe everything's all right?
不太放心
Not exactly.
帶你來真是個錯誤  你該離開了
This was a mistake. You should leave.
早就想走了
Way ahead of you.
喬治沒瞎  瞎的是你
George isn't blind! You're the blind one!
# Baby I've been thinkin' 'bout #
# Runnin' away from you #
# After all you said and done #
# Don't wanna stay with you #
# It seemed like everything we could have done #
# Has passed us by #
# Yeah, I got to get movin' #
# I'm tired of groovin' #
# With someone who can't get high #
# Don't chase me around #
# You're bringin' me down #
# I don't want to play by your rules #
# My life is my own #
# So leave me alone #
# I don't want to be your fool #
你弄的?
You do that?
這不是我的車欸
You know, that's not my car.
是我老闆的車
That's my boss's car.
如果我老闆的車出事  我會倒楣
And if something were to happen to my boss's car, well, I'd get in trouble.
算你運氣好  他有備胎
Lucky for you, his got a spare tire.
# Don't chase me around #
# You're bringin' me down #
# I don't want to play by your rules #
# Don't chase me around #
修好它
Fix it.
去你媽的
Fuck you.
# My life is my own #
# So leave me alone #
# I don't want to be your fool #
- 別打他  - 他弱不禁風
- Leave him alone! - He's a flower!
他弱不禁風
He's a flower, man.
他弱不禁風  他很無知
He's just a flower. He doesn't know better.
女士們
Ladies.
再靠近一步  我就打得他滿地找牙
Come one step closer and I will knock his teeth out.
修好它
Fix it.
至少先給我一塊布擦臉吧
Can I at least get a rag to wipe my face first?
別想
Nope.
先修輪胎
Tire first.
- 日舞  - 在
- Sundance. - Yeah.
上馬去找泰斯  叫他滾過來
Get on a horse, go get Tex and get his ass down here.
好的
Okay.
我愛你
I love you.
泰斯  泰斯
Tex! Tex!
那夏威夷佬在片場修理克連
That Hawaiian guy's back at the ranch kicking Clem's face in.
我操...
Ah, son of a...
我來代替泰斯  這邊請
I'll take over for Tex. Right this way.
駕  駕
Hyah! Hyah!
下午5點  洛杉磯
It's 5:00 in Los Angeles.
# 調頻93 KHJ #
# 93 KHJ #
# All the leaves are brown #
克連  你沒事吧?
Clem, you all right?
# And the sky is gray #
# I went for a walk #
# On a winter's day #
# I'd be safe and warm #
- # If I was in L.A. # - 你好
- # If I was in L.A. # - How do?
- # Oh, California Dreamin' #  - 今天過得很糟  我差點丟盡臉面
- # Oh, California Dreamin' # - What a day. Shit, I almost lost my shit.
# On such a winter's day, hey #
# I went into a church #
# I stopped along the way #
# Well, I got down on my, on my, on my bended knees #
# And I began to pray #
# You know the preacher did succumb #
# He knows I'm going to stay #
# Yes, he knows 'cause I told him so #
# Oh, California dreamin' #
# On such a winter's day, yeah #
呃...
You, uh...
你要進來看我演的《聯邦調查局》嗎?
You want to come in and watch my F.B.I.?
我早想到了  我買了一手啤酒  在想要不要訂個披薩
Why, I just figured we would. I got a six-pack in the back. Thought we'd order a pizza.
好耶
All right.
( 《聯邦調查局》 )
( 聯邦探員旨在保護平民 )
( 並打擊美國政府的敵人 )
長途跋涉18英里
Eighteen miles to Pendleton, Willard.
希望我們一路順風
Any kind of luck, we'll be unloaded
在我孩子睡覺前回家
and back at El Toro before my kids go to bed.
我今天給自己買了迷幻煙
Hey, bought me an acid-dipped cigarette today.
是嗎?
Oh, yeah?
你要買迷幻煙嗎?
You want to buy a cigarette dipped in acid?
是啊
Yeah.
如果我想嗨  就要在這裡嗨
If I'm gonna trip, I want to trip here, man.
去樹林裡散步  而不是在家裡
Walk in the woods. Not in my home.
- 我要藏在這裡  免得當成香煙抽  - 是啊
- Just gonna stash it here. Don't smoke it by mistake. - Yeah.
你想抽就抽  留一點給我就好
You want to smoke some, smoke some. Just save me some.
免了  我不想抽什麼迷幻煙  我有酒就不需要別的
Nah, I don't need to trip out on no acid. My booze don't need no buddy.
開始了
Whoa! Oh!
該我上場了
Here I come. Here I come.
嗯
Mm.
有什麼麻煩嗎  下士?
What's the trouble, corporal?
有輛車跟著我們  長官
There's a truck tailing us, sir.
可能是急著去哪裡的農夫
It might be a farmer in a hurry to get someplace.
好吧
Oh, fine.
- 儘量開快點  - 是  長官
- Well, take it as fast as you can. - Yes, sir.
那是太平洋海岸公路?
That PCH?
是啊  在馬里布
Yeah, yeah. Malibu.
波柯峽谷什麼鬼的  不記得了
Puerco Canyon or some shit. I don't know.
噢  麻煩來了
Uh-oh. Here comes trouble.
嘭  哈哈
Boom! Ha, ha!
哇塞  直接打臉
Oh, man. Right in the face.
- 跳得漂亮  - 多謝誇獎
- That was a smooth leap. - Thank you.
屍體二號
Dead number two.
我喜歡那個鏡頭
I like that shot.
那傢伙超級渾球的
That guy's a fucking prick.
那個是巴比·霍根  是個好人
Um, that's Bobby Hogan. Good guy.
好了  準備看我的大絕招
All right, get ready for my big F.B.I. moment.
- 他們都死了  - 好極了
- They're all dead, babe. - Good.
( 麥可·莫托  盜竊政府財產 )
"麥可·莫托"
"Michael Murtaugh."
- 《聯邦調查局》  - 麥可·莫托
- The F.B.I. - Michael Murtaugh.
賽爾喬·科爾布奇
Buongiorno, Sergio.
轉到第七台  美國廣播公司  《聯邦調查局》
Turn on Channel 7. ABC. F.B.I.
我找到人演你的《內布拉斯加的吉姆》了
I'm watching your Nebraska Jim as we speak.
主演菲力浦·阿伯特  威廉·蘭道
Philip Abbott, William Reynolds.
特邀明星詹姆斯·法倫提洛
With guest stars James Farentino,
瑞克·達爾頓...
Rick Dalton...
喜歡我嚼口香糖嗎?
Like the chewing gum?
- 諾曼·費爾  - 超有男子氣概
- Norman Fell. - Strong.
- 本集單元名  "寂靜街頭"  - "寂靜街頭"
- Tonight's episode: All the Streets Are Silent. - "All the Streets Are Silent."
只要瑞克·達爾頓拿著火爆獵槍就不會寂靜了
Except when Rick Dalton's got a fucking shotgun, I'll tell you that.
說得真他媽好
You're goddamn right.
福特·柯蒂納
New Ford Cortina.
( 六個月後 )
- 看起來真美味  謝謝你  - 請享用  先生
- Well, that looks delicious. Thank you. - Enjoy, sir.
嗯嗯
Mm-mm-mm-mm... Mmm.
在穆索與法蘭客餐廳的午餐會議之後
After that Musso & Frank's lunch meeting,
馬文確實給了瑞克在義大利電影圈工作的機會
Marvin did provide Rick job opportunities in the Italian film industry.
瑞克·達爾頓  我是馬文·施沃茲  稍等
Rick Dalton, Marvin Schwarz here. Hold on.
軒尼詩  加冰塊
Hennessy X.O on the rocks.
好的  施沃茲先生
Yes, Mr. Schwarz.
《內布拉斯加的吉姆》  賽爾喬·科爾布奇執導
Two words. Nebraska Jim, Sergio Corbucci.
什麼內布拉斯加?  賽吉奧是誰啊?
N-Nebraska what? Sergio who?
賽爾喬·科爾布奇
Sergio Corbucci.
他誰啊?
A-and who's that?
全世界第二棒的意式西部片導演
The second-best director of Spaghetti Westerns in the whole wide world.
他在拍一部新的西部片  叫作《內布拉斯加的吉姆》
He's doing a new Western. It's called Nebraska Jim.
而因為我  他在考慮你
And because of me, he's considering you.
後來呢  傑克拿到主角
Well, Rick got Nebraska Jim.
瑞克可是個挺厲害的吉姆
And Rick made a rather compelling Nebraska Jim,
在科爾布奇的反英雄名冊裡還挺上相的
existing quite nicely within Sergio Corbucci's rogues gallery of antiheroes.
在羅馬  瑞克喜歡狗仔隊  也喜歡大家為了他
In Rome, Rick loved the paparazzi and the fuss they made over him
和戲裡的聯玦主演黛芙娜·班克伯所做的排場
and his Nebraska Jim costar Daphna Ben-Cobo.
好了  狗仔們  好了
All right there, paparazzos. All right. Take it easy.
他愛死當地食物  愛到胖了將近七公斤
He loved the food so much that during his stay, Rick gained almost 15 pounds.
但他不喜歡義大利人拍電影的方式
But he didn't love the Italians' way of making movies.
事實上  他覺得  演員在拍歐洲電影時各說各的語言
In fact, he thought the post-synced, "every actor speaks their own language,"
像巴別塔一樣混亂可笑
Tower of Babel shooting style of European movies was ridiculous.
在羅馬時  馬文安排瑞克在另外三部義大利電影演出
While in Rome, Marvin plugged Rick into three other Italian productions.
他的第二部西部片是《死白人說  快幹掉我  林哥》
His second Western was Kill Me Quick, Ringo, Said the Gringo,
主演的還有約瑟夫·考登
also starring Joseph Cotten
導演是卡文·傑克森·派吉特  是喬治·費羅尼的藝名
and directed by Calvin Jackson Padget, pseudonym for Giorgio Ferroni.
他的第三部電影是義大利和西班牙的合拍片
His third was an Italian/Spanish coproduction
和特利·薩瓦拉斯領銜主演
that paired him with Telly Savalas,
由華金·路易士·羅梅羅·馬琴特執導的《紅血紅皮膚》
titled Red Blood, Red Skin, directed by Joaquín Romero Marchent
以及根據佛洛伊·雷·威爾森的小說改編的
and based on the Floyd Raye Wilson novel,
《死的印第安人才是好的印第安人》
The Only Good Indian Is a Dead Indian.
他的第四部電影  是向007詹姆斯·邦德"致敬"的間諜片
And his fourth, a Spaghetti secret agent, James Bond rip-off-type flick called
由安東尼奧·馬格赫特執導的《爆炸行動》
Operazione Dyn-O-Mite!, directed by Antonio Margheriti.
( ↙克裡夫·布茲 )
瑞克在義大利的短暫半年賺了不少
Ultimately making Rick's six-month Italian sojourn fairly profitable,
儘管他把大部份賺來的錢  都花在羅馬的豪宅上了
although his swank Roman apartment ate up a big chunk of his earnings.
當瑞克搭著泛美航空回到好萊塢時
So as Rick returns to Hollywood via Pan Am,
他已拍完四部電影  口袋裡有些錢
he has four new movies under his belt, some money in his pocket,
還有最近剛娶的義大利新星老婆  法蘭切絲卡·卡布奇
and his brand-spanking-new Italian wife, starlet Francesca Cappucci.
在快速飛向新生活和未知前途的同時
Hurtling through the air towards a new life and uncertain future,
瑞克不太確定自己的未來
Rick was really not sure about what lay ahead for him.
在後面大老遠的經濟艙  喝著一杯又一杯的血腥瑪麗
Way back in coach, working on his bottomless Bloody Mary,
克裡夫·布茲也回到洛杉磯
Cliff Booth returned to Los Angeles as well.
他陪著瑞克在義大利整整六個月
He kept Rick company during his entire six-month stay in Italy.
然而  兩人回到家時  達成了協定
( 西班牙《紅血紅皮膚》拍片現場 )
However, as the two men return home, they've come to an understanding.
好  我要說了
Well, here it goes now.
有了...
With the, uh...
我有了新的老婆...
With the new wife, I, uh...
我實在付不出你的薪水了  克裡夫
I just I can't afford you anymore, Cliff.
你懂吧?  我連自己的房子都快負擔不起了
You know? I can barely afford my own house anymore.
所以我計畫賣掉房子
So I think the plan is to sell the house
在多路卡湖買幾間公寓  賺點錢
and buy-buy a condo in-in-in Toluca Lake, bank the money.
你知道  銀行存款生活之類的
You know, live off it. That type of thing.
希望我能拍下一季的試播劇
Hopefully, I score come next pilot season.
那是個好計畫
That's a good plan.
是啊
Yeah. You know,
到時候我就知道還撐不撐得下去
by then, I'll know if I have a career or not,
就像艾迪·歐布萊恩說的  要麼我在洛杉磯生存下來
if I'm a solid Los Angeles citizen like Eddie O'Brien says,
否則我就準備打包回密蘇裡
or if I'm one step closer to going back to Missouri.
這趟歐洲旅行結束後  我想我們...
So when this whole European journey is over, I think we've, uh...
我們就走到盡頭了  克裡夫
We've reached the end of the trail, Cliff.
所以  在九年的合作之後
So these last four Italian flicks,
這四部義大利電影  就是瑞克和克裡夫最後相聚的時光了
after nine years together, would be Rick and Cliff's final rodeo.
克裡夫不知道他要怎麼辦
Cliff doesn't have a clue what he's gonna do.
兩人唯一確定的是
The only thing the two men know of for sure:
今晚  瑞克和克裡夫會照舊大醉一場
Tonight, Rick and Cliff will have a good old-fashioned drunk.
兩人都知道  當飛機降落在瑟袞多時
Both men know, once the plane touches down in El Segundo,
對他們倆都是一個時代的結束
it'll be the end of an era for both of them.
而當你和一個比兄弟更親
And when you come to the end of the line with a buddy
排名只在老婆後面的搭檔走到盡頭時
who is more than a brother and a little less than a wife,
不醉不歸是道別的唯一方式
getting blind drunk together is really the only way to say farewell.
# You don't know what's going on #
# You've been away for much too long #
# You can't come back #
# And think you are still mine #
# You're out of touch, my baby #
# My poor old-fashioned baby #
# I said baby, baby, baby #
# You're out of time #
# Yeah #
# Baby, baby, baby, you're out of time #
# I said baby, baby, baby #
# You're out of time #
這就是家  親愛的
Here it is, honey.
- 你喜歡嗎?  - 我喜歡
- You like it? - I love it.
# Yes, you are left out, yes, you're #
# Left out of there without a doubt 'cause #
# Baby, baby, baby, you're out of time #
你要掛在哪裡?
Where do you want it?
( 時間: 12點30分 )
誰?
Hello?
- 是我瓊安娜  和我的寶寶  - 嗨  上來吧
- Hey, it's Joanna and the baby. - Hi! Come on up.
# But you can't come back #
# And be the first in line #
嗨
Hi!
親愛的  你好嗎?
Oh, honey. How are you?
- 你快生了  - 是呀
- Oh, my gosh, you're about to pop! - I know!
- 是呀  - 噢
- I know. - Oh!
- 這是育嬰室  - 天呐  莎朗
- And this is the nursery. - Oh, my God, Sharon.
- 太完美了  - 你喜歡嗎?
- It's perfect. - Do you love it?
小鞋子
Little shoes!
是呀
I know.
# Baby, baby #
我肚子撐得好大
I'm about to burst.
- 你會成為好母親  - 謝謝
- I think you're gonna be a wonderful mother. - Thank you.
- # I said baby, baby, baby #  - 嗯
- # I said baby, baby, baby # - Mm!
( 時間: 下午3點 )
# You're out of time #
( 時間: 下午5點 )
( 寵物託管所 )
# Left out of there without a doubt 'cause #
- 謝了  吉莉安  - 拜拜
- Thanks, Gillian. - Bye!
拜拜  布蘭蒂
Bye, Brandy!
# Baby, you're out of time #
當時波蘭斯基在倫敦準備下一部電影
Sharon had two friends move into the Cielo Drive residence
莎朗便找了兩個朋友  搬進天堂大道的住宅
while Roman was in London preparing his next movie:
波蘭斯基的波蘭老友  佛泰·法萊考斯基
Voytek Frykowski, an old friend of Roman's from Poland,
和他的社工女友艾碧·嘉佛格
and his girlfriend, social worker Abigail Folger,
她是佛格咖啡帝國的接班人
heiress to the vast Folger coffee empire.
( 中國戲院正在放映《拉斯維加斯男子》 )
( 戲院停車場 )
# Baby, baby #
Baby, you're out of time #
( 正在放映《火山情焰》 )
# I said #
( 《羅密歐與茱麗葉》 )
# Baby, baby, baby #
# You're out of time #
# Yes, you are left out #
# Yes, you're #
# I said you're #
# Left out of there without a doubt 'cause #
# Baby, baby, baby, you're out of time #
# I said baby, baby, baby #
當晚  莎朗和她的兩位客人  當然還有傑·賽布林
That night, Sharon, her two houseguests and, naturally, Jay...
都去了西好萊塢的地標"土狼"墨西哥餐廳吃晚飯
all went to the West Hollywood Mexican restaurant landmark El Coyote, on Beverly, for dinner.
那間成人電影院有活動?
What's going on at the dirty movie place?
有首映會
Oh, they're having a premiere.
成人電影院辦首映會?
Dirty movies have premieres?
對啊  很好玩的
Yeah. They're fun.
- 這地方好繁忙  - 我知道
- This place is always so busy. - I know.
真瘋狂
It's crazy in here.
請坐這裡
And right here for you.
- 男士們  - 謝謝
- Gentlemen. - Oh. Thanks.
將近8點半時
While closer to 8:30,
瑞克和克裡夫到了范杜拉大道上的墨西哥餐廳"維加之家"
Rick and Cliff went to the Valley Mexican restaurant landmark Casa Vega on Ventura.
歡迎光臨
Hello. Welcome.
不客氣
You're welcome, sir.
哎呀呀  這不是眼鏡蛇本人嗎?
Well, well, well, if it ain't the cobra himself.
- 嘿  道格  怎麼樣啊?  - 瑞克  你好嗎?  很高興見到你
- Hey, Doug. What's happening? - Rick, how you doing? It's good to see you.
老婆好嗎?
How's the wife doing?
開玩笑的啦
I'm just kidding. I'm just kidding.
狗狗布蘭蒂留在瑞克家裡
Brandy stayed behind at Rick's house,
守著在床上熟睡的義大利美女
guarding the beautiful Italian woman asleep in her bed
等著克裡夫和瑞克回家...
and waiting for Cliff and Rick to come home...
倒時差的法蘭切絲卡則在睡覺
while jet-lagged Francesca slept.
但你只有給他剪髮的那天才有錢賺吧
But you just get paid for the day that you cut his hair?
不  我一天的薪水是一千美元
No, no, no. I get paid $1000 a day.
我抵達的那天就收一千美元
I get paid $1000 the day I arrive. I get paid $1000...
在"土狼"  大家都開心地喝著瑪格麗特
At El Coyote, margaritas and good times were had by all,
除了莎朗以外
except Sharon.
莎朗因為懷孕感到些許的憂鬱
Sharon was experiencing a touch of pregnancy-induced melancholy.
不只是這樣  當晚也破了當年最熱的紀錄
Not only that, it was later reported that it was the hottest night of the year,
使她更因懷孕而感到不適
and it made her feel especially pregnant in all the worst ways.
我不想再參加派對了  我很累
I don't want to party anymore. I am tired.
因為他有本事
Because he got it done.
不  不是因為他有本事
No, it's not... It's not because he just got it done.
他跟其他的導演有一樣長的檔期
He had just as much time as all the rest of the goddamn directors.
重要的是他的時間管理
What he did with that time... That's what counted.
瑞克和克裡夫在"維加之家"喝了太多酒
At Casa Vega, Rick and Cliff drank so much that,
他們離開時留下了凱迪拉克  搭計程車回家
when they left, they left the Cadillac there and took a cab home.
史上最偉大的動作導演卻最被忽視
The greatest action director, underrated guy of all time.
大約10點
Around 10,
莎朗與她的朋友離開"土狼"回到了家
Sharon and her friends left El Coyote and arrived back at her house.
你大概喝了19杯瑪格麗特
You've had, like, 19 margaritas.
( 《豔侶迷春》 )
他們四人又聚了一會兒
The four of them hung out a little longer,
艾碧嘉甚至替他們彈奏了一曲...
with Abigail even playing the piano for them...
# 別惹我生氣  別撒謊 #
# Don't get me mad Don't tell no lie #
# 別讓我傷心  別不理我 #
# Don't make me sad Don't pass me by #
# 寶貝  你的心裡 #
# Baby, are you holding #
# 是不是沒有我? #
# Holding anything but me? #
# 因為我真得很專一 #
# 'Cause I'm a real Straight shooter #
# 如果你懂我的意思 #
# If you know what I mean #
# 你可以帶給我愛  你可以留在我身邊 #
# You can bring me love, you can hang around #
# 你可以照顧我 #
# You can bring me up #
# 別拋棄我 #
# Don't you bring me down #
直到她回房
until she returned to her room,
抽了根煙  讀起了書
smoked a joint and read a book.
此時大概11點了
That was around 11.
大約同時
At more or less the same time,
佛泰躺在沙發上  大口抽著煙
Voytek laid on the couch watching American television
看著美國電視劇
and thought about how much better it was
覺得比波蘭電視好看很多
than Polish television, as he smoked a big joint.
大約11點10分
Somewhere around 11:10,
莎朗換上舒適的家居服
Sharon changed into her comfy house attire.
覺得好點了嗎?
Feel better?
好超多的
That is drastically better.
過了11點45分
It was after 11:45 by the time
瑞克和克裡夫才在家門口下車
the yellow cab dropped Rick and Cliff in front of the house.
謝謝你  就停這裡
Thank you. Right here.
謝了  夥計  (西班牙語)
All right. Grazie, amigo.
- 多少錢?  - 三美元
- How much do I owe you? - Three dollars.
布蘭蒂看見他們回來很高興
Brandy was glad to see them return.
- 多謝  老兄  - 謝了
- Thank you, brother. - Thanks.
來吧  再來喝瑪格麗特
More margaritas.
大約午夜
Around midnight,
已經醉翻了的瑞克·達爾頓
a completely drunk Rick Dalton started making
開始做瑪格麗特冰沙
a blender of frozen margaritas.
好啦
All right.
我們去散步
We're walking.
同時  克裡夫將狗鏈綁在興奮的布蘭蒂的脖子上
At the same time, Cliff was attaching a leash to an excited Brandy's dog collar.
我知道
I know.
我記得你
I remember you.
迷幻煙?
A cigarette dipped in acid.
- 有什麼功效?  - 抽了會嗨
- What's that do? - You smoke it. It gets you high.
- 多少錢?  - 50美分
- How much? - Fifty cents.
50美分
Fifty cents.
嬉皮女賣的  50美分
Hippie girl, 50 cents.
就是今晚了嗎?
Tonight the night?
有何不可?
Why not?
我們上路囉
And away we go.
我們的波蘭朋友說  這是今年最熱的一天
Our Polish friend said it was the hottest day of the year.
雖然是他說的  但其實也可能是真的
Despite the fact that he said it, actually, it might be true.
# I used to live in New York City #
# Everything there was dark and dirty #
# Outside my window was a steeple #
# With a clock that always said twelve thirty #
# Young girls are coming to the canyon #
# And in the mornings I can see them walking #
# I can no longer keep my blinds drawn #
# And I can't keep myself #
他媽的
Goddamn.
什麼狗屁私人道路
Fucking private road.
付地價稅付到脫褲子  媽的
Damn property taxes up the butt. Goddamn.
一群該死的臭嬉皮
Bunch of goddamn fucking hippies.
搞屁啊?
What the fuck?
喂  你
Hey, you!
對  爛人  我就是說你
Yeah, asshole, I'm talking to you!
大半夜鬧哄哄的
What the hell do you think you're doing
你想炒死人還是怎樣?
bringing that noisy hunk of shit around here at midnight?
這是私人道路  好嗎?
This is a private road, all right?
你是誰?  你來這裡找誰?
Who are you? And who are you here to see?
沒人  先生  我們只是迷路了  找不到方向
Nobody, sir. We just got lost and a little turned around.
放屁
Ah, horseshit.
你們臭嬉皮來暗處吸毒  對吧?
You fucking hippies came up here to smoke dope on a dark road, huh?
下次想來這套  他媽的先修好你的滅音器
Next time you want to try that, fix your fucking muffler.
我們真得很抱歉打擾到你
Look, we're really sorry we disturbed you.
聽著  老兄  你不屬於這裡
Look, chief, you don't belong here.
快把這爛車開走
Now, take this mechanical asshole
給我他媽的離開這條路
and get it off my fucking street!
喂
Hey!
飆車仔  把這爛東西開走
( 鄧尼斯·霍珀主演了嬉皮士電影《逍遙騎士》 )
Dennis Hopper! Move this fucking piece of shit!
好  給我一點時間調頭
All right. Just give me a moment to turn it around.
那就倒退啊  白癡
Drive it backwards, numbnuts,
他媽的開走  現在就開走
but fucking drive it, and drive it now!
好啦好啦  別吼了
Okay. Okay. Stop yelling.
別激動  我們要走了
Hold your horses. We're leaving.
看屁啊  紅發小賤人
The hell are you looking at, you little ginger-haired fucker?
喂  再來這裡我就他媽的報警
Hey, you come around here again, I'm gonna call the fucking cops!
他媽的死嬉皮
Dirty fucking hippies.
住他媽的豪宅  以為自己很有本事噢
There in his fancy fucking house, thinking he's handled it.
但他看到我們了  他醒著  有警覺
But he's seen us. He's awake. He's alert.
他們都還醒著  他們都在聽音樂
They're all awake. They're listening to fucking records.
大家都他媽的醒著
Everybody's fucking awake!
好了
Look!
- 查理怎麼說的?  - 他說:
- What did Charlie say? - He said:
"去泰瑞的老房子  幹掉裡面的所有人"
"Go to Terry's old house and kill everybody in there."
你也聽見他說的了 "要弄得像做過法一樣"
And you heard him yourself. He said, "Make it witchy."
他要是沒說過  我就是騙子
Now, he either said that, or I'm a liar.
你們還有誰要說我是騙子?
Now, are any one of you calling me a liar?
嗯?
Hm?
你呢?
How about you?
你覺得我是騙子嗎?
Are you calling me a liar?
當然不是
No, of course not.
那就好
Good.
等一下
Hold it.
- 剛剛那是瑞克·達爾頓嗎?  - 誰?
- Was that Rick Dalton? - Who?
《賞金律法》裡的那個傢伙
The guy from Bounty Law.
- 誰  傑克·卡希爾?  - 對啊
- Who, Jake Cahill? - Yeah.
路上那傢伙是傑克·卡希爾
That guy in the robe was Jake Cahill.
等等  剛剛吼我的人是他媽的傑克·卡希爾
Wait a minute. That was fucking Jake Cahill that just yelled at me?
他看起來比較老  不過我想是他
He was older, but, yeah, I think so.
- 瑞克又是誰?  - 拜託你  莎蒂  醒一醒
- So who's this Rick guy? - Jesus Christ, Sadie, get it together.
瑞克·達爾頓在五零年代的一出牛仔電視劇《賞金律法》裡飾演傑克·卡希爾
Rick Dalton played Jake Cahill on a cowboy show in the '50s called Bounty Law.
去你媽的  凱蒂
Fuck you, Katie.
很抱歉我不知道五零年代電視上的每個法西斯份子的名字
Sorry I don't know the name of every fascist on TV in the '50s.
我不敢相信那個人是傑克·卡希爾
I can't believe that asshole in the robe was Jake Cahill.
我小時候有一個《賞金律法》便當盒
When I was a kid, I had a Bounty Law lunch box.
那是我最喜歡的便當盒
That was my favorite of all my lunch boxes.
我想到了
Dig this!
當我們在嗨的時候(吸毒)
When we've been having our trip sessions,
我一直在腦子裡想這個絕妙點子
I've been expanding on this one idea in my head.
仔細聽好
All right, dig it.
我們都是看電視長大的  你懂我的意思吧?
We all grew up watching TV, you know what I mean?
如果你是看電視長大的  表示你是看著謀殺長大的
And if you grew up watching TV, that means you grew up watching murder.
嗯哼
Mm-hm.
電視上的每個節目都跟謀殺案有關  除了《我愛露西》
Every show on TV that wasn't I Love Lucy was about murder.
所以  我的點子是...
So my idea is...
我們去殺教我們殺人的人
we kill the people who taught us to kill.
我是說  我們他媽的在哪呢?  是他媽的好萊塢啊
I mean, where the fuck are we, man? We are in fucking Hollywood, man.
整個時代的人們都是看著住在這裡的演員殺人長大的
The people an entire generation grew up watching kill people live here.
而他們該死的吃香喝辣
And they live in pig-shit fucking luxury.
所以  去他們的
I say fuck them.
把他們的雞巴割下來逼他們吃下去
I say we cut their cocks off and make them eat it.
好主意  莎蒂
That's a great idea, Sadie.
你們倆準備好殺豬了嗎?
You two ready to kill some piggies?
等一下  靠
Wait a minute. Oh, shit.
抱歉  我把刀忘在車上了
Sorry, I forgot my knife in the car.
我可以回去拿嗎?
Can I go...? Can I go back and get it?
- 好啊  當然  - 好
- Yeah, sure. - Okay.
- 等一下  - 怎麼了?
- Go on. Wait a minute. - What?
車子上鎖了  你需要鑰匙才能開門
I locked the car. You'll need keys to get in.
噢
Oh.
對噢  謝謝
Right. Thank you.
- 好  我馬上回來  - 好
- Okay. I'll be right back. - Okay.
- 快一點  - 好  一下就好
- Just hurry up. - Yeah, just a little minute.
賤貨
Oh, that fucking bitch!
冷靜
Shh! Calm down.
那邊就有棟房子
There's a fucking house right there.
- 現在怎麼辦?  - 完成我們來此的目的
- What do we do now? - We do what we came to do.
結束後  分頭各自攔車回家
And when we're done, we split up and hitch home.
還有問題嗎?
Any more questions? Hm?
好了  殺豬的  來宰幾隻小豬吧
Okay, pig killers, let's kill some piggies.
好的
All right.
看來你很餓
Oh, someone's hungry.
好了
All right.
是餵食的時候了
It's feeding time.
布蘭蒂  去沙發上
Brandy, couch.
你不要動來...
And don't you mo...
不會吧
Oh, man.
呃...
Uh...
我開始迷糊了
The train has left the station.
靠  我錯了
Bad idea.
哇噢
Whoa.
# 八個人試著進攻 #
# Eighty men tried #
# 八個人死了 #
# And eighty men died #
# 他們埋在一起 #
# Now they're buried together #
# 埋在鄉下 #
# On the countryside #
# 10  20  30  40  50或更多 #
# 10, 20, 30, 40, 50 or more #
# 紅男爵殺紅了眼 #
# The Bloody Red Baron was rollin' up the score #
你繞過去  看看有沒有後門
You go around there, see if there's a back entrance.
好嗎?  去吧
All right? Go.
嘿
Hey.
在這情況下  我盡力了
I am doing the best I can under the circumstances.
我今晚不想跟你吵
Now, I do not want to get into it tonight.
有事嗎?
Uh... can I help you?
靠
Shit.
這裡還有多少人?
How many other people are here?
只有一個在後面睡覺
Oh, just the one sleeping in the back there.
去抓他  帶他來客廳
Go get him and bring him into the living room.
如果他不要呢?
What if he says no?
絕不死心
Don't take no for an answer.
有刀的是你  帶他過來
You're the one with the knife. Get him in here!
嘿
Hey.
你是真的吧?
You are real, right?
我真到假不了  遜咖
I'm as real as a doughnut, motherfucker.
什麼情況?
What the fuck?
- 去客廳  - 怎麼回事?
- Go to the living room. - What is going on, huh?
- 走  - 好啦好啦
- Go! - Okay. Si, si.
- 那他媽的誰啊?  - 我不知道
- Who the fuck's that? - I don't know.
法蘭切絲卡
Francesca.
呃...
Oh. Uh...
什麼...
What...?
我認識你們
Oh, I know you.
我認識你們三個
I know all three of you.
對啦  史潘片場
Yeah. Spahn Ranch.
史潘片場  噢耶
Spahn Ranch. Yeah. Hoo!
我不知道你的名字  但我記得那頭髮
I don't know your name, but I remember that hair.
還有你  我記得你的小白臉
And you, I remember your white little face.
你在騎小馬
And you were on a horsie.
對啦
Yeah.
你是...?
Uh... You are...?
我是魔鬼
I'm the devil,
我來幹魔鬼的勾當
and I'm here to do the devil's business.
不對  是更蠢的名字  像是"瑞斯"之類的
Nah, it was dumber than that. Something like... Rex.
- 射他啦  泰斯  - 泰斯
- God, shoot him, Tex! - Tex.
操
Fuck!
狗日的
Son of a bitch!
喂
Hey, you.
你竟敢闖進我家  王八蛋
How dare you come into my house, motherfucker!
# Keep me hangin' on #
# Get out of my life #
# Why don't you babe? #
- # Why don't you babe? #  - 糟糕
- # Why don't you babe? # - Wow, man.
什麼情況?
What the fuck?
老天爺
Jesus Christ.
哇靠
Holy shit.
法蘭切絲卡  親愛的
Francesca! Francesca, honey!
封鎖天堂大道
10,000 block, Cielo Drive.
先生  你對抗入侵者時  大約是幾點鐘?
Around what time was it when you confronted the intruder?
大概午夜吧
It was about midnight.
- 大概午夜?  - 對
- Around midnight? - Yeah.
你怎麼知道?
How do you know it was midnight?
嗯  我在廚房
Well, I was, uh... I was in the kitchen.
我在調瑪格麗特...
You know, I was making margaritas, and, uh...
我聽到汽車減音器的噪音很吵
I heard the sound of a noisy muffler.
我抬頭看時間
I looked up at the clock.
廚房的時鐘顯示是午夜
It said... The kitchen clock said midnight.
正好12點?
Twelve o'clock exactly?
有可能是12點5分之類的
I mean, it could have been 12:05. Something like that.
你沒有再見到他捫  直到那女人在泳池攻擊你
And you didn't see them again until the woman attacked you in the pool.
對
No, no.
所以  這些行兇者做了什麼?
So, what did these perpetrators do?
行兇者?  他們是臭嬉皮
Perpetrators? They were hippie assholes.
其中兩個人從前門那裡破門而入
Two of them burst through the front door there,
那個男嬉皮說他是魔鬼
and the guy hippie said he was the devil.
然後他說  "我來幹魔鬼的勾當"
And he said, "I'm here to... do some devil shit."
大概是這麼說的吧
Or... That's not verbatim, but...
- "魔鬼的勾當"?  - 對啊  "魔鬼的勾當"
- "Some devil shit"? - Yeah, "devil shit."
我們上路囉
And away we go.
嘿  等一下
Hey. Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
你去哪間醫院  克裡夫?  我們在那裡見吧?
What hospital you going to, Cliff? I'll meet you there, huh?
你不會想在醫院見我的
You don't want to meet me in no hospital.
你去照顧你的老婆吧
Why don't you go take care of your lady.
她剛吞了五顆他媽的安眠藥
Hey, she just took five fucking sleeping pills.
她會睡到哥倫比亞日
She'll be asleep till Columbus Day.
你們可能得再來一趟把她弄醒呢
These guys will probably have to come out here again just to wake her ass up.
我死不了啦
Hey, I'm not gonna die.
我可能會瘸腿  但死不了
I may get a limp, but I ain't gonna die.
- 我時候未到  老兄  - 對
- It's not my time yet, man. - All right.
所以不需要在等候室等我
So no use waiting in some waiting room.
你去脫光和那美人躺好
Why don't you go lie naked with that fine creature.
明天來看我  要帶貝果
Come visit me tomorrow. Bring bagels.
你想替我做什麼的話  就照顧狗狗布蘭蒂
You want to do something for me, check on Brandy.
她可能有點受驚嚇
She may be a little shook up after that.
- 她會想跟你一起睡  - 開玩笑
- She may want to sleep with you. - Are you kidding me?
她正和法蘭切絲卡睡
She's sleeping with Francesca right now.
你可能沒法帶她回去了
You might never get her back. Ha, ha.
- 我們得走了  - 好了  克裡夫
- We got to go. - All right, then, Cliff.
那明天見了
I'll see you tomorrow, then.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
你是個好朋友  克裡夫
You're a good friend, Cliff.
我儘量
I try.
哈羅?
Hello?
嗨
Hey.
我是傑·塞布林  波蘭斯基的朋友
I'm Jay Sebring. I'm a friend of the Polanskis.
你是瑞克·達爾頓  對吧?
You're Rick Dalton, right?
是啊  我是瑞克·達爾頓
Yeah. Yeah. I'm Rick Dalton.
- 住在隔壁  - 我知道
- Live next door. - Oh, I know.
我會取笑莎朗說  她住在傑克·卡希爾隔壁
I tease Sharon that she lives next door to Jake Cahill.
如果她想雇人取羅曼的頭顱  只要到隔壁就好  對吧?
If she ever wants to put a bounty on Roman, she just has to go next door, right?
真的假的
No shit.
究竟怎麼回事?
What the fuck happened?
那些是些嬉皮怪人
Oh, th-these fucking hippie weirdos,
他們闖進我家
they-they-they broke into my house.
什麼意思  他們想搶劫你?
What do you mean, like, trying to rob you?
我們不知道他們想幹嘛
We don't know what the fuck they wanted.
是要搶我嗎?  我不知道
Were they robbing me? I don't know.
嗨過頭情緒失控了?  誰知道?
Were they freaking out on some bummer trip? Who knows?
但他們想殺我老婆和我好朋友
But they tried to kill my wife and my buddy.
- 老天呐  你說的是真的嗎?  - 是啊  他媽的千真萬確
- Jesus Christ. Are you serious? - Yeah, I'm fucking serious.
我好朋友和他的狗幹掉其中兩個  然後...
Now, my buddy and his dog killed two of them, and then...
靠  我燒了最後一個
Well, shit. I-I torched the last one.
- "燒"?  - 對啊
- "Torched"? - Yeah.
我把她烤焦了
I burnt her ass to a crisp.
- 怎麼做的?  - 信不信由你
- How'd you do that? - Well, believe it or not, I...
我的工具室裡有一把噴火器
I got a flamethrower in my toolshed.
《麥克拉斯基的14拳》裡面那把?
Oh, from The Fourteen Fists of McCluskey.
對
Yeah!
Yeah. Yeah.
就那是把
That's... That's the one.
而且還能用  感謝上帝
Yeah, it still works too. Thank God.
大家都沒事吧?
Is everybody okay?
肯定的是那些死嬉皮有事
Well, the fucking hippies aren't, that's for goddamn sure.
但我沒事
Yeah. But I'm fine.
我老婆也沒事
You know, my wife's fine.
我們只是有點受驚嚇
We're just a little shook up, is all.
- 我的天啊  真可怕  - 是啊
- Oh, my God, that's terrifying. - Yeah.
傑  親愛的  一切還好嗎?
Jay, honey, is everything all right?
一切都好  親愛的
Everything's okay now, honey.
但有幾個嬉皮闖進隔壁鄰居家
But some hippies broke into the house next door.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
嚇死人了
Oh, that's terrifying.
大家都沒事吧?
Is everybody okay?
我正在和你隔壁鄰居聊這件事
I'm talking to your next-door neighbor about it right now.
瑞克·達爾頓?
Rick Dalton?
是啊  是我
Yeah, that's me. Heh.
你好啊  鄰居
Oh. Well, hello, neighbor.
大家都沒事吧?
Is everybody okay?
是啊  莎朗  大家都沒事
Yes, Sharon, everybody's fine.
你還好嗎?
Are you okay?
我很好  謝謝你關心
Well, yes, I am. Thank you for asking that.
瑞克  你要上來喝一杯嗎?
Rick, would you like to come up to the house
見見我的朋友如何?
for a drink and meet my other friends?
好啊  謝謝
Yeah, sure. Thank you.
噢耶  太好了  我幫你開門
Oh, hooray! Great. I'll buzz you up.
來吧
Come on.
- 嘿  很高興認識你啊  - 是啊
- Hey, nice to meet you, huh? - Yeah.
- 傑·塞布林  - 嗨  很榮幸
- Jay Sebring. - Hey, pleasure.
- 是啊  - 很榮幸  傑
- Yeah. - Pleasure, Jay.
我也很榮幸
Pleasure's all mine.
你今晚過得驚心動魄
Sounds like you had a hell of a night.
- 瑞克  - 莎朗  嗨
- Hey, Rick. - Sharon, hi.
- 真高興認識你  - 我也很榮幸
- So nice finally to meet you. - My pleasure.
他們是我的朋友
They are my friends.
瑞克·達爾頓  他是個很棒的演員
Rick Dalton, he's a wonderful actor.
進屋來坐吧
Yes, come up and inside.
( 從前... )
( 有個好萊塢 )
( 編劇及導演: 昆汀·塔倫蒂諾 )
( 別走開  後面還有彩蛋 )
大家好  我是瑞克·達爾頓
Hi. This is Rick Dalton,
以賞金獵人傑克·卡希爾聞名
better known as bounty hunter Jake Cahill,
我來代言紅蘋果香煙
speaking on behalf of Red Apple cigarettes.
我抽紅蘋果香煙已經好幾年了
Now, I smoke Red Apples. Been smoking them for years.
1892年就有紅蘋果煙草公司
But since the Red Apple tobacco company's been around since 1862,
你也會看到傑克·卡希爾抽紅蘋果香煙
you'll see Jake Cahill smoke Red Apple too.
過去在傑克的年代  紅蘋果是袋裝煙草
Now, back in Jake's day, Red Apple came in a pouch,
他得自己捲煙
and he had to roll his own.
但現在紅蘋果  出廠時已經卷好
But today, Red Apple comes factory-rolled.
用最好的煙草風味  達到最好的哈煙體驗
For the best drag with the best tobacco flavor,
讓你的喉嚨減輕灼熱感
with less burn on your throat
不像其他未過濾的香煙
than any other non-filtered cigarette.
嗯
Mm!
這才是香煙的味道  哼
Now, that's the way a cigarette should taste. Hm.
更好抽  更多風味  更不傷喉
Better drag, more flavor, less throat burn.
就是紅蘋果的風格
That's the Red Apple way.
尋找我傑克·卡希爾的人像立牌
So look for this life-size standee of me, Jake Cahill,
販賣優質紅蘋果香煙的地方
wherever fine Red Apple tobacco products are sold.
來一口  好好感受
Take a bite and feel all right.
來一口紅蘋果
Take a bite of a Red Apple.
就說是傑克派你來的
Tell them Jake sent you.
卡
And cut.
這煙難抽死了
This cigarette tastes like fucking shit.
對了  誰選這張爛照片的?
And, by the way, who chose this photo?
我有雙下巴欸
I have a double chin. All right?
你們都瞎了嗎?
Nobody notices that crap?
EN by Enwansix, TW-Theatrical by s9111355
Revised by Aray 2019/09/16
字幕修訂: 非傲慢即偏見@SubHD
最後修訂日期: 2019/11/22
( 播放1966年至1968年電視劇《蝙蝠俠》主題曲 )